<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>jonas.place</title>
  <subtitle></subtitle>
  <link href="https://jonas.place/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://jonas.place/"/>
  
    <updated>2023-04-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  
  <id>https://jonas.place</id>
  <author>
    <name>Jonas Purmann</name>
    <email></email>
  </author>
  
    
    <entry>
      <title>Going back to Japan</title>
      <link href="https://jonas.place/posts/going-back-to-japan/"/>
      <updated>2023-04-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>https://jonas.place/posts/going-back-to-japan/</id>
      <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[
      <p><img src="/images/japan00/2023-03-25_171013_00.jpg" alt="Picture of Cherry Blossoms"></p>
<p>In about 60 hours from now, I will take a plane to Japan.
It has been about seven years since I last stepped foot in this beautiful country.
This will be my fourth time to go to Japan. I am eager to find out, what has changed and what stayed the same.</p>
<p>I am super excited to go back and will report on the journey as I go. Follow along if you care to get some updates.</p>

    ]]>
      </content>
    </entry>
  
    
    <entry>
      <title>Tokyo, first 48 hours</title>
      <link href="https://jonas.place/posts/tokyo-first-48-hours/"/>
      <updated>2023-04-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>https://jonas.place/posts/tokyo-first-48-hours/</id>
      <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[
      <p>Yesterday, we arrived in Tokyo. It was a quite stressful day and I didn't have much time to take any pictures. We went to</p>
<ul>
<li>Get a translation of my german Drivers License into japanese</li>
<li>Buy Train tickets for the following days which took close to one hour</li>
<li>Reserve bus tickets, also for upcoming holidays, stay tuned.</li>
<li>Explore the area surrounding our hotel for a bit</li>
<li>…and that was it!</li>
</ul>
<p>Today however was different.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Check out an interactive Map of the places we visited <a href="https://wanderlog.com/view/ipgoeoyijw/japan-trip/shared">here</a>. I will update this map as we continue our Journey.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>We started today in Ginza, to check out the Flagship Store of Muji, a quite famous department store where we bought a nail scissor (or something close to it, surprinsingly hard to find nail scissors in Japan).
<img src="/images/japan02/2023-04-29_121510_00.JPG" alt="image">
Aparently, there is a christian church in the middle of Ginza in this architecturaly stunning building.</p>
<p>We had Sushi for Breakfast that was pretty great, afterwards we went to another department Store: LOFT, where we found this:
<img src="/images/japan02/2023-04-29_141222_00.JPG" alt="what is that supposed to be">
&quot;Cha&quot; Means tea in Japanese. Apparently you can buy tea that has been placed inside cigarette shells… Only in Japan.</p>
<p><img src="/images/japan02/2023-04-29_144349_00.JPG" alt="image">
This one was shot right outside the LOFT department store, I love high contrast shots like this.</p>
<p>We then went on to Yoyogi park and Meiji Shrine.
<img src="/images/japan02/2023-04-29_163003_00.JPG" alt="image">
Right outside Meiji Shrine, you can find those Sake barrels wrapped in straw that were gifted to Emperor Meiji for his accomplishments.
<img src="/images/japan02/2023-04-29_163233_00.JPG" alt="image">
We then ate <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dango">Dango</a>, A japanese Snack, typically eaten at festivals in Japan. It consists of Rice Cake covered in Sweet and Salty sauce.</p>
<p><img src="/images/japan02/2023-04-29_165545_00.jpg" alt="image">
We checked out Takeshita Dori next which was so crowded that we immediately left again
<img src="/images/japan02/2023-04-29_171808_00.JPG" alt="image">
Instead, we checked out Cat alley, which was way more calm, this and the following two pictures are taken of a side street of Cat Street. Quite lovely.</p>
<p><img src="/images/japan02/2023-04-29_173321_00.JPG" alt="image">
<img src="/images/japan02/2023-04-29_174553_00.JPG" alt="image"></p>
<p>We finished the evening by going to Monzennakacho which is a bit off the beaten path in Tokyo. Didn't see many tourists there (or anyone for that matter) but the shops were quite pleasing to look at in the light of the already set sun. The rest of the pictures in this post are from Monzennakacho.
<img src="/images/japan02/2023-04-29_182755_00.JPG" alt="image">
<img src="/images/japan02/2023-04-29_182945_00.JPG" alt="image">
<img src="/images/japan02/2023-04-29_191257_00.JPG" alt="image">
We ate at &quot;Daruma&quot; were we were the only foreigners in sight. The waitress was quite friendly and served us tasty dishes. What a day!</p>

    ]]>
      </content>
    </entry>
  
    
    <entry>
      <title>Last day in Tokyo</title>
      <link href="https://jonas.place/posts/last-day-in-tokyo/"/>
      <updated>2023-04-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>https://jonas.place/posts/last-day-in-tokyo/</id>
      <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[
      <p>Tonight, we felt the Jetlag for the first time for real. We both couldn't sleep until 2AM. Either way, we woke up at 9AM to get used to the Japanese Time. The Sun in Japan rises before 5AM and sets shortly after 6PM, so there is not much time to enjoy the daylight if you get up too late.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Check out an interactive Map of the places we visited <a href="https://wanderlog.com/view/ipgoeoyijw/japan-trip/shared">here</a>. I will update this map as we continue our Journey. This post is about Day 3.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Today was a public holiday. In most of the city, not much was going on. In other areas, everyone was shopping. I tried to reflect that contrast with the pictures I selected for this post.</p>
<p>It had been raining the night before. This created a nice atmosphere in the city.</p>
<p><img src="/images/japan03/2023-04-30_095756_00.JPG" alt="A man cleaning up in front of a supermarket">
A man cleaning up in front of a supermarket.</p>
<p><img src="/images/japan03/2023-04-30_101428_00.JPG" alt="A park ranger patrolling at a Japanese Playground">
A park ranger patrolling at a Japanese Playground. Coming from Germany, it is quite bizzare to see people at parks and playgrounds whose only job it is, to keep the vicinity of the park safe.</p>
<p><img src="/images/japan03/2023-04-30_110509_00.JPG" alt="We had breakfast and coffee at Blue Bottle coffee in Roppongi">
We had breakfast and coffee at Blue Bottle coffee in Roppongi. It used to be very hard to find places where you can enjoy food and beverages outside… Now I saw way more shops in Tokyo where you can eat and drink while <em>also</em> sitting outside. Quite the nice change, if you ask me. Anyway, Blue bottle Coffee was always one of the coffee shops, where you could sit outside. It is a hipster place with hipster prices but I quite enjoy the surrounding area and the calm and quiet right next to otherwise busy areas of the city.</p>
<p><img src="/images/japan03/2023-04-30_111629_00.JPG" alt="Koinobori in a public park in Japan">
Since it is now golden Week in Japan, the longest stretch of public holidays in a row, there are a few festivities associated with these occasions. These fishes are called <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Koinobori">Koinobori</a> and are flown for Childrens day in Japan which is at May 5 this year. Childrens Day marks the end of the public holiday season that is Golden Week.</p>
<p><img src="/images/japan03/2023-04-30_112420_00.JPG" alt="Cityscape of Tokyo">
I just love cityscapes like that. Here you can see, how few cars were on the road today.</p>
<p><img src="/images/japan03/2023-04-30_123800_00.JPG" alt="Fruits and vegetables store">
Our destination of the day was Chazawa-dori in Sangenjaya, a shopping street that is closed for car traffic on Sunday. It is lined with pretty shops, restaurant and cafés but also traditional stores, local stores and just regular fruit and vegetable stores like this one pictured here.</p>
<p><img src="/images/japan03/2023-04-30_123940_00.JPG" alt="Life Size King Kong Figure">
For some reason, there is a giant King Kong Figure, picking up a small girl hanging from the side of a building. Check the scale of the people compared to the statue!</p>
<p><img src="/images/japan03/2023-04-30_124729_00.JPG" alt="Small Coffee Shop in Chazawa-dori">
Small shops like this (in this case a coffee shop) are the reason I love Japan so much. Just look at all the details!</p>
<p><img src="/images/japan03/2023-04-30_133035_00.JPG" alt="Entrance to Shimokitazawa">
At the end of Chazawa-dori, you can find Shimokitazawa, a very popular area that gained a lot of popularity since I first visited Japan in 2014. This area is known for second hand clothing and furniture and also has a lot of restaurants. As you can see, it was packed! Everyone was using their day off to do a bit of shopping and catch up with friends.</p>
<p><img src="/images/japan03/2023-04-30_150211_00.JPG" alt="Playing Shogi in the streets">
There was a tournament of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shogi">Shogi</a> (also called Japanese Chess) held in the streets. It was quite interesting to watch. Bystanders were very engaged with every move the players did.</p>
<p><img src="/images/japan03/2023-04-30_150538_00.JPG" alt="Front door with technology and beautiful decay">
Beautiful mess of colors, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wabi-sabi">Wabisabi</a> (beautiful decay) and technology.</p>
<p><img src="/images/japan03/2023-04-30_182803_00.JPG" alt="Wooden House in modern City">
This traditional japanese wooden house is close to our hotel and stands in stark contrast to the rest of the surrounding, which is super modern.</p>

    ]]>
      </content>
    </entry>
  
</feed>