<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>jonas.place</title>
  <subtitle></subtitle>
  <link href="https://jonas.place/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://jonas.place/"/>
  
    <updated>2023-05-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  
  <id>https://jonas.place</id>
  <author>
    <name>Jonas Purmann</name>
    <email></email>
  </author>
  
    
    <entry>
      <title>Going back to Japan</title>
      <link href="https://jonas.place/posts/going-back-to-japan/"/>
      <updated>2023-04-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>https://jonas.place/posts/going-back-to-japan/</id>
      <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[
      <p><img src="/images/japan00/2023-03-25_171013_00.jpg" alt="Picture of Cherry Blossoms"></p>
<p>In about 60 hours from now, I will take a plane to Japan.
It has been about seven years since I last stepped foot in this beautiful country.
This will be my fourth time to go to Japan. I am eager to find out, what has changed and what stayed the same.</p>
<p>I am super excited to go back and will report on the journey as I go. Follow along if you care to get some updates.</p>

    ]]>
      </content>
    </entry>
  
    
    <entry>
      <title>Tokyo, first 48 hours</title>
      <link href="https://jonas.place/posts/tokyo-first-48-hours/"/>
      <updated>2023-04-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>https://jonas.place/posts/tokyo-first-48-hours/</id>
      <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[
      <p>Yesterday, we arrived in Tokyo. It was a quite stressful day and I didn't have much time to take any pictures. We went to</p>
<ul>
<li>Get a translation of my german Drivers License into japanese</li>
<li>Buy Train tickets for the following days which took close to one hour</li>
<li>Reserve bus tickets, also for upcoming holidays, stay tuned.</li>
<li>Explore the area surrounding our hotel for a bit</li>
<li>…and that was it!</li>
</ul>
<p>Today however was different.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Check out an interactive Map of the places we visited <a href="https://wanderlog.com/view/ipgoeoyijw/japan-trip/shared">here</a>. I will update this map as we continue our Journey.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>We started today in Ginza, to check out the Flagship Store of Muji, a quite famous department store where we bought a nail scissor (or something close to it, surprinsingly hard to find nail scissors in Japan).
<img src="/images/japan02/2023-04-29_121510_00.JPG" alt="image">
Aparently, there is a christian church in the middle of Ginza in this architecturaly stunning building.</p>
<p>We had Sushi for Breakfast that was pretty great, afterwards we went to another department Store: LOFT, where we found this:
<img src="/images/japan02/2023-04-29_141222_00.JPG" alt="what is that supposed to be">
&quot;Cha&quot; Means tea in Japanese. Apparently you can buy tea that has been placed inside cigarette shells… Only in Japan.</p>
<p><img src="/images/japan02/2023-04-29_144349_00.JPG" alt="image">
This one was shot right outside the LOFT department store, I love high contrast shots like this.</p>
<p>We then went on to Yoyogi park and Meiji Shrine.
<img src="/images/japan02/2023-04-29_163003_00.JPG" alt="image">
Right outside Meiji Shrine, you can find those Sake barrels wrapped in straw that were gifted to Emperor Meiji for his accomplishments.
<img src="/images/japan02/2023-04-29_163233_00.JPG" alt="image">
We then ate <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dango">Dango</a>, A japanese Snack, typically eaten at festivals in Japan. It consists of Rice Cake covered in Sweet and Salty sauce.</p>
<p><img src="/images/japan02/2023-04-29_165545_00.jpg" alt="image">
We checked out Takeshita Dori next which was so crowded that we immediately left again
<img src="/images/japan02/2023-04-29_171808_00.JPG" alt="image">
Instead, we checked out Cat alley, which was way more calm, this and the following two pictures are taken of a side street of Cat Street. Quite lovely.</p>
<p><img src="/images/japan02/2023-04-29_173321_00.JPG" alt="image">
<img src="/images/japan02/2023-04-29_174553_00.JPG" alt="image"></p>
<p>We finished the evening by going to Monzennakacho which is a bit off the beaten path in Tokyo. Didn't see many tourists there (or anyone for that matter) but the shops were quite pleasing to look at in the light of the already set sun. The rest of the pictures in this post are from Monzennakacho.
<img src="/images/japan02/2023-04-29_182755_00.JPG" alt="image">
<img src="/images/japan02/2023-04-29_182945_00.JPG" alt="image">
<img src="/images/japan02/2023-04-29_191257_00.JPG" alt="image">
We ate at &quot;Daruma&quot; were we were the only foreigners in sight. The waitress was quite friendly and served us tasty dishes. What a day!</p>

    ]]>
      </content>
    </entry>
  
    
    <entry>
      <title>Last day in Tokyo</title>
      <link href="https://jonas.place/posts/last-day-in-tokyo/"/>
      <updated>2023-04-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>https://jonas.place/posts/last-day-in-tokyo/</id>
      <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[
      <p>Tonight, we felt the Jetlag for the first time for real. We both couldn't sleep until 2AM. Either way, we woke up at 9AM to get used to the Japanese Time. The Sun in Japan rises before 5AM and sets shortly after 6PM, so there is not much time to enjoy the daylight if you get up too late.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Check out an interactive Map of the places we visited <a href="https://wanderlog.com/view/ipgoeoyijw/japan-trip/shared">here</a>. I will update this map as we continue our Journey. This post is about Day 3.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Today was a public holiday. In most of the city, not much was going on. In other areas, everyone was shopping. I tried to reflect that contrast with the pictures I selected for this post.</p>
<p>It had been raining the night before. This created a nice atmosphere in the city.</p>
<p><img src="/images/japan03/2023-04-30_095756_00.JPG" alt="A man cleaning up in front of a supermarket">
A man cleaning up in front of a supermarket.</p>
<p><img src="/images/japan03/2023-04-30_101428_00.JPG" alt="A park ranger patrolling at a Japanese Playground">
A park ranger patrolling at a Japanese Playground. Coming from Germany, it is quite bizzare to see people at parks and playgrounds whose only job it is, to keep the vicinity of the park safe.</p>
<p><img src="/images/japan03/2023-04-30_110509_00.JPG" alt="We had breakfast and coffee at Blue Bottle coffee in Roppongi">
We had breakfast and coffee at Blue Bottle coffee in Roppongi. It used to be very hard to find places where you can enjoy food and beverages outside… Now I saw way more shops in Tokyo where you can eat and drink while <em>also</em> sitting outside. Quite the nice change, if you ask me. Anyway, Blue bottle Coffee was always one of the coffee shops, where you could sit outside. It is a hipster place with hipster prices but I quite enjoy the surrounding area and the calm and quiet right next to otherwise busy areas of the city.</p>
<p><img src="/images/japan03/2023-04-30_111629_00.JPG" alt="Koinobori in a public park in Japan">
Since it is now golden Week in Japan, the longest stretch of public holidays in a row, there are a few festivities associated with these occasions. These fishes are called <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Koinobori">Koinobori</a> and are flown for Childrens day in Japan which is at May 5 this year. Childrens Day marks the end of the public holiday season that is Golden Week.</p>
<p><img src="/images/japan03/2023-04-30_112420_00.JPG" alt="Cityscape of Tokyo">
I just love cityscapes like that. Here you can see, how few cars were on the road today.</p>
<p><img src="/images/japan03/2023-04-30_123800_00.JPG" alt="Fruits and vegetables store">
Our destination of the day was Chazawa-dori in Sangenjaya, a shopping street that is closed for car traffic on Sunday. It is lined with pretty shops, restaurant and cafés but also traditional stores, local stores and just regular fruit and vegetable stores like this one pictured here.</p>
<p><img src="/images/japan03/2023-04-30_123940_00.JPG" alt="Life Size King Kong Figure">
For some reason, there is a giant King Kong Figure, picking up a small girl hanging from the side of a building. Check the scale of the people compared to the statue!</p>
<p><img src="/images/japan03/2023-04-30_124729_00.JPG" alt="Small Coffee Shop in Chazawa-dori">
Small shops like this (in this case a coffee shop) are the reason I love Japan so much. Just look at all the details!</p>
<p><img src="/images/japan03/2023-04-30_133035_00.JPG" alt="Entrance to Shimokitazawa">
At the end of Chazawa-dori, you can find Shimokitazawa, a very popular area that gained a lot of popularity since I first visited Japan in 2014. This area is known for second hand clothing and furniture and also has a lot of restaurants. As you can see, it was packed! Everyone was using their day off to do a bit of shopping and catch up with friends.</p>
<p><img src="/images/japan03/2023-04-30_150211_00.JPG" alt="Playing Shogi in the streets">
There was a tournament of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shogi">Shogi</a> (also called Japanese Chess) held in the streets. It was quite interesting to watch. Bystanders were very engaged with every move the players did.</p>
<p><img src="/images/japan03/2023-04-30_150538_00.JPG" alt="Front door with technology and beautiful decay">
Beautiful mess of colors, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wabi-sabi">Wabisabi</a> (beautiful decay) and technology.</p>
<p><img src="/images/japan03/2023-04-30_182803_00.JPG" alt="Wooden House in modern City">
This traditional japanese wooden house is close to our hotel and stands in stark contrast to the rest of the surrounding, which is super modern.</p>

    ]]>
      </content>
    </entry>
  
    
    <entry>
      <title>To the Japanese Alps</title>
      <link href="https://jonas.place/posts/to-the-japanese-alps/"/>
      <updated>2023-05-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>https://jonas.place/posts/to-the-japanese-alps/</id>
      <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[
      <p><img src="/images/japan04/2023-05-01_073306_00.JPG" alt="View from our hotel window">
View from our hotel window in the morning</p>
<p>Today, we woke up early at around 7:30 AM and left for Shinjuku Station to reach our next destination: The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Japanese_Alps">Japanese Alps</a>. We got up so early in fact, that we had an hour to waste at Shinjuku Station. After looking for a Bento (Lunchbox) but failing to find one, we decided to go to the only(!) Café, we could see in the vicinity. The food was okay, nothing to write home about. Then we checked out our train - and found Bento!
It was being sold directly on the platform of our departure. Pretty convenient. (Later I found out, that all the rest of the shops and restaurants were on a completely different floor of the station… Japan, you can be confusing at times.)</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Check out an interactive Map of the places we visited <a href="https://wanderlog.com/view/ipgoeoyijw/japan-trip/shared">here</a>. I will update this map as we continue our Journey. This post is about Day 4.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><img src="/images/japan04/2023-05-01_093107_00.JPG" alt="Drinks in Train form">
The Bento-Shop sold Drinks in the form of little Trains, why not?</p>
<p>Our train left Shinjuku punctually at 10 AM sharp – and we were off. The weather was nice, the train was spotless, the Wi-Fi on the train worked. Everything was dandy!</p>
<p><img src="/images/japan04/2023-05-01_111309_00.JPG" alt="Image of Bento on a Train">
After about 2 hours of riding the train, I decided to crack open my Bento box. It was underwhelmingly bland but did the job of making me less hungry.</p>
<p>This is also, where things went south. There was a signal disturbance that affected our train. We had to make an impromptu stop and then nothing happened for about 1:30 hours. Except for the train clerk anouncing over and over again that they were sorry and that there was a problem with the signal and that they are working to fix it and that it would probably be fixed soon.</p>
<p>We reached our transfer station just one minute late for us to catch our connecting train to our destination. So we had to wait another hour. So all in all, I had a lot of time to think about and observe the behaviour of people. Some things I noted were:</p>
<ul>
<li>Japanese people don't wear sunglasses (Of course some do but surprisingly little. During our trip I saw 2 Japanese people out of maybe 100 that would wear sunglasses and - as said - it was a sunny day today)</li>
<li>On our route, there was very little renewable energy and thinking back, I never noticed wind power in all my travels in Japan. Also, there was only one solar park on the whole route from Tokyo to the Japanese Alps.</li>
<li>People traveling to the Japanese Alps are serious about hiking. Most people wore functional clothes, hiking boots, some even walking/hiking sticks, even though the terrain in the Japanese alps is easy to moderate compared to most hiking routes in Austria/Switzerland/Norway…</li>
<li>There are amazing restrooms everywhere but most of them don't have soap in them. So prepare to bring your own sanitizer!</li>
</ul>
<p><img src="/images/japan04/2023-05-01_162426_00.JPG" alt="image">
At 3:45 PM, we reached our destination: Narai-Juku! A post-town in the Japanese Alps. These towns were laying on the route of the post transports between Kyoto and Tokyo. A few hundred years later, a lot of the houses are still pretty well kept and people still actually still work an live here – mostly in the tourism industry of course.</p>
<p>We checked into our Minshuku (Guest House) shortly after arriving. It is located right in the town center with very pretty houses all around!</p>
<p>We walked around in Narai-Juku and found some cute shops. We had such a lovely &quot;talk&quot; (we tried to communicate in all the ways possible) with an elderly lady that sold us handmade postcards that her deceased husband made (they were 1€ each). Encounters like this make the trip to Japan completely worth it!
<img src="/images/japan04/2023-05-01_165947_00.JPG" alt="image">
At 5PM, most of the shops close and thus, most of the people leave Narai-Juku. Finally, we could take some pictures without people in them!
<img src="/images/japan04/2023-05-01_170440_00.JPG" alt="image">
I didn't realise, that cars could also pass through this ancient town which kind of &quot;ruins the vibe&quot; but I guess it's necessary since this town is still actively lived in and not only a backdrop for pretty pictures.
<img src="/images/japan04/2023-05-01_172200_00.JPG" alt="image">
Anyway, here's the last picture of pretty houses (for today).
<img src="/images/japan04/2023-05-01_180155_00.JPG" alt="image">
At 6 PM it was dinner time. I was pretty hungry before so I had a few nuts.</p>
<p>The dinner started with just a few plates, pictured above. Our host gave us only this much information about the proceedings of the evening: &quot;Dinner is served between 6 PM and 7:15 PM&quot;. I thought: Good, that I ate some nuts before since this is not much at all! Next, our host brought out boiled vegetables that we could dip into a sauce that he prepared. Pretty nice but I was still hungry, I ate two bowls of rice with that. There were a lot more courses to follow after that though:</p>
<ul>
<li>Clam chowder</li>
<li>Grilled Trout</li>
<li>Horse Sashimi (delicious with garlic sauce!)</li>
<li>Tempura</li>
<li>Miso Soup</li>
<li>Fruits</li>
<li>Ice cream</li>
</ul>
<p>I left about 2kg heavier than before. Everything was delicious, prepared with care and served with love. I was happily surprised!
<img src="/images/japan04/2023-05-01_161343_00.JPG" alt="image">
We finished the evening by going to the bath in the Guest House which was reserved especially for us! It was a Japanese Sento: A bath were you wash yourself before resting in the hot water (thermal bath). It is soo relaxing to feel the warmth on your tired muscles.</p>
<p>Aparently, in Japan, my name is Mr. Jonas.</p>

    ]]>
      </content>
    </entry>
  
    
    <entry>
      <title>Hiking the Nakasendo</title>
      <link href="https://jonas.place/posts/hiking-the-nakasendo/"/>
      <updated>2023-05-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>https://jonas.place/posts/hiking-the-nakasendo/</id>
      <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[
      <p>We  left our Minshuku without breakfast to hurry to the Narai Train Station at 8:30 AM. There was only one train leaving at 8:40 AM and the next one was leaving at after 11 AM. Luckily, we got our train and rode it for 1:30 hours to Nagiso. From there, the hiking started.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Check out an interactive Map of the places we visited <a href="https://wanderlog.com/view/ipgoeoyijw/japan-trip/shared">here</a>. I will update this map as we continue our Journey. This post is about Day 5.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The Nakasendo is the path connecting the post towns and you can &quot;hike&quot; it. Most of the path is paved or has cobblestones on it. There are some steep sections though but nothing that warrants the use of special hiking gear.</p>
<p><img src="/images/japan05/2023-05-02_113201_00.JPG" alt="Tsumago Juku">
After about 45 minutes of hiking, we reached Tsumago-Juku. This Post Town looks a lot like Narai but has a lot more greenery both inside the town and surrounding it. <s>Even though it is Golden Week right now, there were not that many tourists, as you can see yourself in this picture (it was taken at 11:30 AM).</s></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Correction: It totally wasn't golden week as we found out one day later. Golden week started at 3rd of May 2023 and the Post Towns got significantly more crowded.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>We had some snacks in Tsumago and continued our hike in the direction of Magome Juku, the last post town along our Journey.
<img src="/images/japan05/2023-05-02_122118_00.JPG" alt="Nakasendo">
Most of the Nakasendo looks exactly like this. Not too hard to hike on, well structured with big signs guiding you along the way.</p>
<p>Other things to note about the Nakasendo:</p>
<ul>
<li>There are public toilets every 500 Metres along the Nakasendo! They were clean but none had any soap.</li>
<li>People live along the hiking trail in beautiful villages/single homes with pretty gardens.</li>
<li>The scenery changes constantly: from forests to clearings to hills to settlements… It does not get boring at all. There were some parts where we had to hike alongside a road because part of the hiking trail were closed though.</li>
<li>If you don't want to hike but still want to visit the towns, you can just go by car/bus/train and still see most of the beauty that the Nakasendo has to offer (and be much less sweaty for it).</li>
</ul>
<p><img src="/images/japan05/2023-05-02_143223_00.JPG" alt="Beware of bears on the Nakasendo">
There is one challenge though: The Nakasendo is in bear territory. Signs are warning you constantly about possible encounters with bears. To keep bears at bay, you should create lots of noises. Luckily, the Nakasendo is equipped with lots of bells that you should ring when passing by to warn the bears about your arrival.
<img src="/images/japan05/2023-05-02_133755_00.JPG" alt="Tea kettle">
At about the halfway point between Tsumago and Magome, there is a tea house which serves free tea. The tea is boiled in this kettle over an open flame.
<img src="/images/japan05/2023-05-02_142630_00.JPG" alt="Garden Image">
Just after reaching the outskirts of Magome, we found this private garden of a local who invited us to have a look. It was quite chaotic and cluttered but beautiful in its own way. I like this Maple tree in front of the small pond (which had chairs and tables in it for some reason).
<img src="/images/japan05/2023-05-02_144837_00.JPG" alt="Lookout point before Magome">
There was a lookout point just before entering the town that is Magome Juku. In the background, you can see some of the lower Japanese Alps.
<img src="/images/japan05/2023-05-02_161917_00.JPG" alt="Flowers in front of a shop in Magome Juku">
In Magome Juku (but also along the whole Nakasendo), there were a lot of beautiful flowers that were just in bloom here. Compared to Tokyo, where Spring is almost over, the colder climate of the Japanese Alps makes for a later bloom of flowers, comparable to the time they bloom in northern Germany.
<img src="/images/japan05/2023-05-02_161209_00.JPG" alt="Gohei Mochi in a shop in the sun">
After arriving in Magome, we checked into our hotel, got some rest and then explored the town more. We found a shop which sells this type of Mochi called Gohei Mochi (there are many shops like this on the Nakasendo but this is one of them). These are delicious. Compared to other types of Mochi, which are completely smooth inside, this type of mochi has some rice particles still left intact. Thus it has a less doughy type of texture. The sauce was the king of the show and tastes sweet and savory at the same time, similar to Dango. Also similar to dango, Gohei Mochi is grilled over an open flame.
<img src="/images/japan05/2023-05-02_181021_00.JPG" alt="Magome Juku empty">
After 6 PM, most of the people left Magome Juku and we could take some picture like that. Tough I think this is the last picture of post town for this journey.</p>
<p>In summary:<br>
It was a pretty uneventful day. We hiked a lot, had lots of snacks along the way and saw amazingly beautiful scenery. Sadly, this beauty does not translate that well into pictures (or I am just a bad photographer) but I am not so happy with the pictures I got from today. As beautiful as the post towns are, there are only so many pictures you can take of them without getting bored.</p>

    ]]>
      </content>
    </entry>
  
    
    <entry>
      <title>Relaxing in the Japanese Countryside</title>
      <link href="https://jonas.place/posts/relaxing-in-the-japanese-countryside/"/>
      <updated>2023-05-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>https://jonas.place/posts/relaxing-in-the-japanese-countryside/</id>
      <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[
      <p>This post is about the last two days of our journey in Japan. On day 6, we spent the rest of the day in Magome and then travelled to the Japanese countryside. Today (day 7), we just relaxed a lot.</p>
<h1>Day 6 - Magome</h1>
<p>Yesterday, we started the day in Magome-Juku. The original plan was to catch a bus in the next larger city, Nakatsugawa and then go to the countryside from there. But as we realised, this bus also goes through Magome-Juku… So we rebooked the bus from Magome-Juku leaving at 3 PM. So we had to pass the day in Magome somehow. We had a great coffee at <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/HillBilly+Coffee+Company/@35.5251473,137.5631691,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m6!3m5!1s0x601cb6fd476935ed:0x5b18e4a4d4bb7679!8m2!3d35.525143!4d137.565744!16s%2Fg%2F11dxsvnwbn">Hillbilly Coffe</a> (an actual Hipster Coffee Place in a historic town… how great is that?) which served me one of the best cappucinos I ever had.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Check out an interactive Map of the places we visited <a href="https://wanderlog.com/view/ipgoeoyijw/japan-trip/shared">here</a>. I will update this map as we continue our Journey. This post is about Day 6 and 7.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><img src="/images/japan07/2023-05-03_134013_00.JPG" alt="Overcrowded Magome-Juku">
Compared to the days before, there were a lot more people in the Magome-Juku. This is, because Golden Week started on the 3rd of May (I was wrongly writing that it started prior to that). With that many people, Magome-Juku was a lot less fun.<br>
By the way, the blue thing you see in the picture above (left side of the picture) is some kind of Pokémon Go Stop. The whole town of Magome had signs for Pokémon Go which kind of ruined the quaint vibe a bit.
<img src="/images/japan07/2023-05-03_105740_00.JPG" alt="Magome Juku the non-touristy parts">
So we decided to check out the parts of Magome-Juku that were not overrun by tourists. Just by leaving the main street and walking 200 Metres, you end up in places like this were you cannot see a tourist at all. Pretty nice!
<img src="/images/japan07/2023-05-03_105935_00.JPG" alt="This is a bus stop in Magome-Juku">
By the way: This is a bus stop in Magome-Juku!
<img src="/images/japan07/2023-05-03_135552_00.JPG" alt="Dogs with hats">
There were a lot of people with dogs in Magome-Juku and they were all wearing some kind of costume or hats… I don't know what that was about but it was quite fun.</p>
<p>We had a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kaiseki">Kaiseki</a>-Lunch at one of the best Japanese Restaurants I ever set foot in in Magome-Juku, <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/Haginoya/@35.5239346,137.5650787,20.88z/data=!4m14!1m7!3m6!1s0x601cb6fd476935ed:0x5b18e4a4d4bb7679!2sHillBilly+Coffee+Company!8m2!3d35.525143!4d137.565744!16s%2Fg%2F11dxsvnwbn!3m5!1s0x601cb6e2c93ad075:0x312a253ac85c0bd2!8m2!3d35.5238588!4d137.5653563!16s%2Fg%2F1ttpgzj2">Haginoya</a>. We were seated in a private room and were served five courses. Everyting was sourced locally and tasted great (I'll spare you the details of each course). And at the end we paid around 5000 yen for two people which is equivalent to around 34 €. Amazing deal for the money!</p>
<p>We caught the bus, which took us to Sawando where we had booked the Airbnb for the night.
<img src="/images/japan07/2023-05-03_164234_00.JPG" alt="Shrine in the Mountain">
After about 1.5 hours, we arrived in Sawando. The town of Sawando is nothing special. A bit of industry, some restaurants and a highway to the towns nearby. We walked 15 Minutes from the bus stop to our Airbnb which was a bit up the hill and away from the busyness of the road and the town. The image above captures the spirit of the way to the Airbnb.</p>
<p>We checked into the Airbnb and walked back to Sawando Center to grab Dinner.</p>
<h1>Day 7 – Sawando</h1>
<p>We relaxed a lot today.</p>
<p><img src="/images/japan07/2023-05-04_125233_00.JPG" alt="Garden of Airbnb">
The cottage that we stayed in was in a beautiful garden. There even was a tiny pond where some frogs live. We could hear the frogs croaking at night which was relaxing.
<img src="/images/japan07/2023-05-04_083101_00.JPG" alt="View of the Cottage">
The Airbnb was very small but big enough for two people two comfortably live/sleep in. It was so nice to wake up and see a surrounding like this.
<img src="/images/japan07/2023-05-04_084424_00.JPG" alt="Industrial area">
In the morning, I went to a 7-Eleven in Sawando to get breakfast – Pancakes with maple Syrup and Mini Croissants. Sawando does not offer great sights and so I took pictures of the everyday life of a small town in Japan. Here you can see the entrance of an industrial builduing close to the 7-Eleven that I walked to.
<img src="/images/japan07/2023-05-04_090557_00.JPG" alt="The way up the mountain to our Airbnb">
The way up the mountain to the Airbnb looks like this and is just so lovely.
<img src="/images/japan07/2023-05-04_113949_00.jpg" alt="Momo-Chan">
The Airbnb we stayed at has a Shiba Inu Dog called Momo-Chan. At noon, we took Momo-Chan on a walk to a café nearby. She behaved amazingly well for being on a walk with us for the first time. I just love her friendly face!
<img src="/images/japan07/2023-05-04_120827_00.JPG" alt="Abandoned Truck">
In the japanese countryside, you can find a lot of abandoned buildings and vehicles. They can make for some pretty interesting shots like the one above.
<img src="/images/japan07/2023-05-04_121544_00.JPG" alt="Mountainscape in Sawando">
The mountainscape of the Japanese Alps around Sawando is very nice to look at.
<img src="/images/japan07/2023-05-04_121731_00.JPG" alt="Small Shop">
We passed by a small shop on our way back from the walk and saw this small shop which sold snacks. The owner, an elderly woman tried to communicate somewhat successfully but couldn't get her point accros. She fetched her daughter who is an English teacher to translate. Daughter and Mother don't see many tourists. Sawando is not in any guide books and does not have any (!) hotels. Both daughter and mother were totally sweet. The daughter is also an artist and showed us her pastel paintings. We bought some postcards to send back to Germany.
<img src="/images/japan07/2023-05-04_122142_00.JPG" alt="Detail in Sawando with Mirror">
Some flowers in a window and a mirror in front of the shop described above.</p>
<p>And… that was pretty much the seventh day in Japan. Other than that we washed our clothes, organised stuff, called back home and enjoyed the sunlight and the warmth that the countryside has to offer.</p>
<p>Tomorrow will be an interesting day as we will travel about 6 hours in total with 5 differrent trains to reach the next destination which is also in a Japanese village but even more remote than Sawando.<br>
The things you do to avoid the masses of tourists at Golden Week…</p>

    ]]>
      </content>
    </entry>
  
    
    <entry>
      <title>A day spent in trains</title>
      <link href="https://jonas.place/posts/a-day-spent-in-trains/"/>
      <updated>2023-05-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>https://jonas.place/posts/a-day-spent-in-trains/</id>
      <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[
      <p>We spent the day today traveling. We took the first train at 8:12 AM and reached our accomodation at 3:15 PM. So in total, we travelled over 7 hours. It was pretty warm as well with 26° C and a lot of local trains were not air conditioned. So it was an exhausting day and not many pictures were taken.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Check out an interactive Map of the places we visited <a href="https://wanderlog.com/view/ipgoeoyijw/japan-trip/shared">here</a>. I will update this map as we continue our Journey. This post is about Day 8.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Our destination today were the historic villages of Gokayama. The traditional houses there make up for some pretty unique sights. They are built in a particular style called <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Minka">Gassho-Zukuri</a>. We made the choice to go to this remote location to avoid the big crowds of Golden week in major touristic hotspots.</p>
<p><img src="/images/japan08/2023-05-05_120027_00.jpg" alt="View of Japanese Alps">
We took ALL the trains (plus a bus at the end). From the slow local trains that stop everywhere to the Shinkansen that reaches top speeds of over 200 km/h there was a nice variety. The views of the Japanese Alps were pretty spectacular as you can see above.</p>
<p>One thing we learned today: Taking trains during golden week is <em>fine</em>. They can get crowded which can be a bit unpleasant but it is not as bad as I would have thought. Sometimes you have to stand for a couple of minutes before a seat becomes available and that's about the most uncomfotable it gets.
<img src="/images/japan08/2023-05-05_144232_00.jpg" alt="Earthquake alert">
When reaching Gokayama, all the phones in the bus were sounding an alarm for an earthquake that would have &quot;strong shaking&quot;. The sound of the alarm startled me. I asked myself what I should do with the information to best prepare myself for &quot;strong shaking&quot; but I couldn't think of anything. A couple seconds later, there was a mild shifting back and forth (like a bus usually does anyway  ) and that was it. Later that day, there was another alert in the accomodation and this one was a bit more noticeable. But all in all I am pretty excited that after 3 trips in Japan, I finally experienced an earthquake!
<img src="/images/japan08/2023-05-05_145344_00.jpg" alt="Gassho-Zukuri Houses at the Entrance of Kaminashi">
When we got out at our bus stop, we already saw some Gassho-Zukuri style houses at the entrance of our village that we stayed in for the night.</p>
<p>The following two images show the surroundings of the village. Yeah, it is pretty remote!
<img src="/images/japan08/2023-05-05_145906_00.jpg" alt="Village with river">
<img src="/images/japan08/2023-05-05_150630_00.jpg" alt="Remote location with road">
When we finally arrived at the accomodation, we just laid on the floor for an hour or so. We ate dinner and played some cards and called it a day.</p>

    ]]>
      </content>
    </entry>
  
    
    <entry>
      <title>Gokayama</title>
      <link href="https://jonas.place/posts/gokayama/"/>
      <updated>2023-05-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>https://jonas.place/posts/gokayama/</id>
      <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[
      <p>Today, we checked out the UNESCO World heritage site that is Gokayama. We went to the village of Ainokura where we saw traditional <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Minka">Gassho-Zukuri</a>-houses. It was a relaxed day at the countryside.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Check out an interactive Map of the places we visited <a href="https://wanderlog.com/view/ipgoeoyijw/japan-trip/shared">here</a>. I will update this map as we continue our Journey. This post is about Day 9.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><img src="/images/japan09/2023-05-06_091834_00.jpg" alt="Exile house">
Small house in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Minka">Gassho-Zukuri</a> style that was used as an exile house for people that misbehaved in the village to expel them from the community. This hut is the only exile hut remaining in Japan, it is just a replica though.
<img src="/images/japan09/2023-05-06_093031_00.JPG" alt="Inside the Gassho-Zukuri house">
We also visitied a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Minka">Gassho-Zukuri</a> house and saw the insides of it. These houses are quite spacious but they also had to fulfill a lot of functions. This is what we learned about the house that we visited:</p>
<ul>
<li>It housed more than 20 people.</li>
<li>It was used to keep cattle as well as people.</li>
<li>The upper floor was used to house Silk Moth Caterpillars to make traditional Japanese clothes from.</li>
<li>The steep angle of the roof was useful to keep masses of snow from collapsing the house.</li>
<li>All the houses were built without a single nail.</li>
</ul>
<p><img src="/images/japan09/2023-05-06_112732_00.JPG" alt="Gassho-Zukuri House in Ainokura">
We walked to Ainokura, which is one of three Gokayama villages that you can visit. Ainokura is medium-sized compared to the other two villages. It has about 20 <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Minka">Gassho-Zukuri</a> houses in total. In some of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Minka">Gassho-Zukuri</a> houses in Ainokura, people are actually still living in. Some houses are used as accomodations for tourists, others are used as museums or restaurants.
<img src="/images/japan09/2023-05-06_105746_00.jpg" alt="Mountain Panorama in Ainokura">
There are not only <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Minka">Gassho-Zukuri</a> houses in Ainokura. It also has other, non-historic buildings like the one pictured above. As you can see, the surrounding mountains make up for a beautiful backdrop of the whole village.
<img src="/images/japan09/2023-05-06_115409_00.JPG" alt="Ainokura View">
There is one particular photo-spot in Ainokura, that you <em>have</em> to go to and it is <a href="https://www.google.de/maps/place/Ainokura+Panoramic+Viewpoint/@36.4277733,136.9317984,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m6!3m5!1s0x5ff817ad533e09c7:0xa38c22e844c1d5d4!8m2!3d36.427769!4d136.9343733!16s%2Fg%2F11f9z0hsx6">this one</a>. Of course, we went there and took the picture above.
<img src="/images/japan09/2023-05-06_125909_00.JPG" alt="Road back home with bent road boundaries">
We spent about 2 hours in Ainokura (we also had some small coffee and ice cream there) and then went back to our accomodation. The way back is paved but no cars are allowed on this road. I loved these three road boundaries that get increasingly more bent from left to right.
<img src="/images/japan09/2023-05-06_141238_00.JPG" alt="Wild Wisteria growing close to a river">
In all of Japan, you can see a lot of wild Wisteria growing and hanging from trees. Right now, they are in bloom in the regions we travelled to which is always a beautiful sight.
<img src="/images/japan09/2023-05-06_141948_00.JPG" alt="Sign leading you to our hostel">
The place we stayed at is quite remote. Luckily, there is a sign on the road, guiding you the correct way. Otherwise it's kind of irritating to walk on a country road without any pedestrian walkway in the middle of nowhere.</p>

    ]]>
      </content>
    </entry>
  
    
    <entry>
      <title>Kanazawa, Part I</title>
      <link href="https://jonas.place/posts/kanazawa-part-i/"/>
      <updated>2023-05-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>https://jonas.place/posts/kanazawa-part-i/</id>
      <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[
      <p>Golden week is finally over! It's time to go back to the tourist hotspots. Our first hotspot is Kanazawa. A city that I did not know that much about. Apparently, before and during the Edo Period, this city was pretty rich and thus has a lot of very interesting sights to see!</p>
<p>Kanazawa is called the Seatlle of Japan (because of a lot of rain/wind) and today, it gave us exactly that: A lot of rain. The rain didn't even stop for one second.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Check out an interactive Map of the places we visited <a href="https://wanderlog.com/view/ipgoeoyijw/japan-trip/shared">here</a>. I will update this map as we continue our Journey. This post is about Day 10.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><img src="/images/japan10/2023-05-07_103004_00.JPG" alt="Mountains in fog">
In the morning, we left Gokayama by Highway Bus. The mountains were foggy and looked mysterious.</p>
<p>We reached Kanazawa around noon which was too early to check into our Airbnb. That's why we took some time to explore the city on foot. Kanazawa is not that big and so it does not take long to walk from the central station to pretty much all touristy spots.
<img src="/images/japan10/2023-05-07_125143_00.JPG" alt="Wine bar">
If you are into western-style bars/cafés/restaurants, you are in for a treat in Kanazawa. There are so many cute and interesting places that have a pretty western style. Esther was reminded of the UK with some places. The picture above shows a wine bar. I love how the ivy gives the building a lot of character.
<img src="/images/japan10/2023-05-07_132802_00.jpg" alt="Back-alley with green and beer crates">
Kanazawa is extremely green. One upside of having a lot of precipitation, I guess.
<img src="/images/japan10/2023-05-07_133532_00.JPG" alt="Samurai District front yard">
After about 15 minutes of walking, we reached the Samurai District, Nagamachi. In this district, a lot of the historical places where the Samurai (the highest cast of the ancient Japanese society) lived.
<img src="/images/japan10/2023-05-07_133827_00.JPG" alt="Alley in Nagamachi, the samurai district">
The rain made for some interesting views of this district. Not a lot of people where around and Esther and me were in photography heaven. We took so many pictures.
<img src="/images/japan10/2023-05-07_143556_00.JPG" alt="Fishes in a Samurai House">
We also visited a traditional Samurai house, Nomura-ke. In contrast to a lot of the Samurai-houses in Japan, this one was still in the state it was in, when the Samurai lived in it. The garden of the house was extremely beautiful with Koi fishes, a waterfall, lots of pretty plants and so on. We partook in a tea ceremony which was just wonderful in this setting.
<img src="/images/japan10/2023-05-07_145319_00.JPG" alt="Modern architecture in Kanazawa">
Kanazawa also has some interesting modern architecture. In this shot, I like the reflection of the surfaces that reflect back light from different directions.
<img src="/images/japan10/2023-05-07_145914_00.JPG" alt="Pink staircase">
This pink monochrome staircase is very mesmerizing. It just appeared out of nowhere and caught my attention immediately.
<img src="/images/japan10/2023-05-07_150244_00.JPG" alt="Beautiful Mess in a back-alley">
In contrast to the very organized and clean look, that a lot of old and new buildings in Japan have, there is also this completely messy side of Japan. Those electricity metres, combined with the umbrella and random wires sticking out of the wall are something that I am not used to see in Germany.
<img src="/images/japan10/2023-05-07_183712_00.JPG" alt="Heavy rainfall">
The rainfall got worse and worse over time. Our shoes were getting wetter and wetter. Luckily, we bought umbrellas earlier so the rest of our clothes were fine.
<img src="/images/japan10/2023-05-07_183819_00.JPG" alt="image">
<img src="/images/japan10/2023-05-07_192712_00.JPG" alt="image"></p>

    ]]>
      </content>
    </entry>
  
</feed>