<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>jonas.place</title>
  <subtitle></subtitle>
  <link href="https://jonas.place/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://jonas.place/"/>
  
    <updated>2023-04-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  
  <id>https://jonas.place</id>
  <author>
    <name>Jonas Purmann</name>
    <email></email>
  </author>
  
    
    <entry>
      <title>Going back to Japan</title>
      <link href="https://jonas.place/posts/going-back-to-japan/"/>
      <updated>2023-04-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>https://jonas.place/posts/going-back-to-japan/</id>
      <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[
      <p><img src="/images/japan0/2023-03-25_171013_00.jpg" alt="Picture of Cherry Blossoms"></p>
<p>In about 60 hours from now, I will take a plane to Japan.
It has been about seven years since I last stepped foot in this beautiful country.
This will be my fourth time to go to Japan. I am eager to find out, what has changed and what stayed the same.</p>
<p>I am super excited to go back and will report on the journey as I go. Follow along if you care to get some updates.</p>

    ]]>
      </content>
    </entry>
  
    
    <entry>
      <title>Tokyo, first 48 hours</title>
      <link href="https://jonas.place/posts/tokyo-first-48-hours/"/>
      <updated>2023-04-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>https://jonas.place/posts/tokyo-first-48-hours/</id>
      <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[
      <p>Yesterday, we arrived in Tokyo. It was a quite stressful day and I didn't have much time to take any pictures. We went to</p>
<ul>
<li>Get a translation of my german Drivers License into japanese</li>
<li>Buy Train tickets for the following days which took close to one hour</li>
<li>Reserve bus tickets, also for upcoming holidays, stay tuned.</li>
<li>Explore the area surrounding our hotel for a bit</li>
<li>…and that was it!</li>
</ul>
<p>Today however was different.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Check out an interactive Map of the places we visited <a href="https://wanderlog.com/view/ipgoeoyijw/japan-trip/shared">here</a>. I will update this map as we continue our Journey.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>We started today in Ginza, to check out the Flagship Store of Muji, a quite famous department store where we bought a nail scissor (or something close to it, surprinsingly hard to find nail scissors in Japan).
<img src="/images/japan2/2023-04-29_121510_00.JPG" alt="image">
Aparently, there is a christian church in the middle of Ginza in this architecturaly stunning building.</p>
<p>We had Sushi for Breakfast that was pretty great, afterwards we went to another department Store: LOFT, where we found this:
<img src="/images/japan2/2023-04-29_141222_00.JPG" alt="what is that supposed to be">
&quot;Cha&quot; Means tea in Japanese. Apparently you can buy tea that has been placed inside cigarette shells… Only in Japan.</p>
<p><img src="/images/japan2/2023-04-29_144349_00.JPG" alt="image">
This one was shot right outside the LOFT department store, I love high contrast shots like this.</p>
<p>We then went on to Yoyogi park and Meiji Shrine.
<img src="/images/japan2/2023-04-29_163003_00.JPG" alt="image">
Right outside Meiji Shrine, you can find those Sake barrels wrapped in straw that were gifted to Emperor Meiji for his accomplishments.
<img src="/images/japan2/2023-04-29_163233_00.JPG" alt="image">
We then ate <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dango">Dango</a>, A japanese Snack, typically eaten at festivals in Japan. It consists of Rice Cake covered in Sweet and Salty sauce.</p>
<p><img src="/images/japan2/2023-04-29_165545_00.jpg" alt="image">
We checked out Takeshita Dori next which was so crowded that we immediately left again
<img src="/images/japan2/2023-04-29_171808_00.JPG" alt="image">
Instead, we checked out Cat alley, which was way more calm, this and the following two pictures are taken of a side street of Cat Street. Quite lovely.</p>
<p><img src="/images/japan2/2023-04-29_173321_00.JPG" alt="image">
<img src="/images/japan2/2023-04-29_174553_00.JPG" alt="image"></p>
<p>We finished the evening by going to Monzennakacho which is a bit off the beaten path in Tokyo. Didn't see many tourists there (or anyone for that matter) but the shops were quite pleasing to look at in the light of the already set sun. The rest of the pictures in this post are from Monzennakacho.
<img src="/images/japan2/2023-04-29_182755_00.JPG" alt="image">
<img src="/images/japan2/2023-04-29_182945_00.JPG" alt="image">
<img src="/images/japan2/2023-04-29_191257_00.JPG" alt="image">
We ate at &quot;Daruma&quot; were we were the only foreigners in sight. The waitress was quite friendly and served us tasty dishes. What a day!</p>

    ]]>
      </content>
    </entry>
  
</feed>