<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>jonas.place</title>
  <subtitle></subtitle>
  <link href="https://jonas.place/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://jonas.place/"/>
  
    <updated>2024-11-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
  
  <id>https://jonas.place</id>
  <author>
    <name>Jonas Purmann</name>
    <email></email>
  </author>
  
    
    <entry>
      <title>Going back to Japan</title>
      <link href="https://jonas.place/posts/going-back-to-japan/"/>
      <updated>2023-04-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <id>https://jonas.place/posts/going-back-to-japan/</id>
      <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[
      <p><img src="/images/japan00/2023-03-25_171013_00.jpg" alt="Picture of Cherry Blossoms"></p>
<p>In about 60 hours from now, I will take a plane to Japan.
It has been about seven years since I last stepped foot in this beautiful country.
This will be my fourth time to go to Japan. I am eager to find out, what has changed and what stayed the same.</p>
<p>I am super excited to go back and will report on the journey as I go. Follow along if you care to get some updates.</p>

    ]]>
      </content>
    </entry>
  
    
    <entry>
      <title>Tokyo, first 48 hours</title>
      <link href="https://jonas.place/posts/tokyo-first-48-hours/"/>
      <updated>2023-04-29T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <id>https://jonas.place/posts/tokyo-first-48-hours/</id>
      <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[
      <p>Yesterday, we arrived in Tokyo. It was a quite stressful day and I didn't have much time to take any pictures. We went to</p>
<ul>
<li>Get a translation of my german Drivers License into japanese</li>
<li>Buy Train tickets for the following days which took close to one hour</li>
<li>Reserve bus tickets, also for upcoming holidays, stay tuned.</li>
<li>Explore the area surrounding our hotel for a bit</li>
<li>…and that was it!</li>
</ul>
<p>Today however was different.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Check out an interactive Map of the places we visited <a href="https://wanderlog.com/view/ipgoeoyijw/japan-trip/shared">here</a>. I will update this map as we continue our Journey.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>We started today in Ginza, to check out the Flagship Store of Muji, a quite famous department store where we bought a nail scissor (or something close to it, surprinsingly hard to find nail scissors in Japan).
<img src="/images/japan02/2023-04-29_121510_00.JPG" alt="image">
Aparently, there is a christian church in the middle of Ginza in this architecturaly stunning building.</p>
<p>We had Sushi for Breakfast that was pretty great, afterwards we went to another department Store: LOFT, where we found this:
<img src="/images/japan02/2023-04-29_141222_00.JPG" alt="what is that supposed to be">
&quot;Cha&quot; Means tea in Japanese. Apparently you can buy tea that has been placed inside cigarette shells… Only in Japan.</p>
<p><img src="/images/japan02/2023-04-29_144349_00.JPG" alt="image">
This one was shot right outside the LOFT department store, I love high contrast shots like this.</p>
<p>We then went on to Yoyogi park and Meiji Shrine.
<img src="/images/japan02/2023-04-29_163003_00.JPG" alt="image">
Right outside Meiji Shrine, you can find those Sake barrels wrapped in straw that were gifted to Emperor Meiji for his accomplishments.
<img src="/images/japan02/2023-04-29_163233_00.JPG" alt="image">
We then ate <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dango">Dango</a>, A japanese Snack, typically eaten at festivals in Japan. It consists of Rice Cake covered in Sweet and Salty sauce.</p>
<p><img src="/images/japan02/2023-04-29_165545_00.jpg" alt="image">
We checked out Takeshita Dori next which was so crowded that we immediately left again
<img src="/images/japan02/2023-04-29_171808_00.JPG" alt="image">
Instead, we checked out Cat alley, which was way more calm, this and the following two pictures are taken of a side street of Cat Street. Quite lovely.</p>
<p><img src="/images/japan02/2023-04-29_173321_00.JPG" alt="image">
<img src="/images/japan02/2023-04-29_174553_00.JPG" alt="image"></p>
<p>We finished the evening by going to Monzennakacho which is a bit off the beaten path in Tokyo. Didn't see many tourists there (or anyone for that matter) but the shops were quite pleasing to look at in the light of the already set sun. The rest of the pictures in this post are from Monzennakacho.
<img src="/images/japan02/2023-04-29_182755_00.JPG" alt="image">
<img src="/images/japan02/2023-04-29_182945_00.JPG" alt="image">
<img src="/images/japan02/2023-04-29_191257_00.JPG" alt="image">
We ate at &quot;Daruma&quot; were we were the only foreigners in sight. The waitress was quite friendly and served us tasty dishes. What a day!</p>

    ]]>
      </content>
    </entry>
  
    
    <entry>
      <title>Last day in Tokyo</title>
      <link href="https://jonas.place/posts/last-day-in-tokyo/"/>
      <updated>2023-04-30T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <id>https://jonas.place/posts/last-day-in-tokyo/</id>
      <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[
      <p>Tonight, we felt the Jetlag for the first time for real. We both couldn't sleep until 2AM. Either way, we woke up at 9AM to get used to the Japanese Time. The Sun in Japan rises before 5AM and sets shortly after 6PM, so there is not much time to enjoy the daylight if you get up too late.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Check out an interactive Map of the places we visited <a href="https://wanderlog.com/view/ipgoeoyijw/japan-trip/shared">here</a>. I will update this map as we continue our Journey. This post is about Day 3.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Today was a public holiday. In most of the city, not much was going on. In other areas, everyone was shopping. I tried to reflect that contrast with the pictures I selected for this post.</p>
<p>It had been raining the night before. This created a nice atmosphere in the city.</p>
<p><img src="/images/japan03/2023-04-30_095756_00.JPG" alt="A man cleaning up in front of a supermarket">
A man cleaning up in front of a supermarket.</p>
<p><img src="/images/japan03/2023-04-30_101428_00.JPG" alt="A park ranger patrolling at a Japanese Playground">
A park ranger patrolling at a Japanese Playground. Coming from Germany, it is quite bizzare to see people at parks and playgrounds whose only job it is, to keep the vicinity of the park safe.</p>
<p><img src="/images/japan03/2023-04-30_110509_00.JPG" alt="We had breakfast and coffee at Blue Bottle coffee in Roppongi">
We had breakfast and coffee at Blue Bottle coffee in Roppongi. It used to be very hard to find places where you can enjoy food and beverages outside… Now I saw way more shops in Tokyo where you can eat and drink while <em>also</em> sitting outside. Quite the nice change, if you ask me. Anyway, Blue bottle Coffee was always one of the coffee shops, where you could sit outside. It is a hipster place with hipster prices but I quite enjoy the surrounding area and the calm and quiet right next to otherwise busy areas of the city.</p>
<p><img src="/images/japan03/2023-04-30_111629_00.JPG" alt="Koinobori in a public park in Japan">
Since it is now golden Week in Japan, the longest stretch of public holidays in a row, there are a few festivities associated with these occasions. These fishes are called <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Koinobori">Koinobori</a> and are flown for Childrens day in Japan which is at May 5 this year. Childrens Day marks the end of the public holiday season that is Golden Week.</p>
<p><img src="/images/japan03/2023-04-30_112420_00.JPG" alt="Cityscape of Tokyo">
I just love cityscapes like that. Here you can see, how few cars were on the road today.</p>
<p><img src="/images/japan03/2023-04-30_123800_00.JPG" alt="Fruits and vegetables store">
Our destination of the day was Chazawa-dori in Sangenjaya, a shopping street that is closed for car traffic on Sunday. It is lined with pretty shops, restaurant and cafés but also traditional stores, local stores and just regular fruit and vegetable stores like this one pictured here.</p>
<p><img src="/images/japan03/2023-04-30_123940_00.JPG" alt="Life Size King Kong Figure">
For some reason, there is a giant King Kong Figure, picking up a small girl hanging from the side of a building. Check the scale of the people compared to the statue!</p>
<p><img src="/images/japan03/2023-04-30_124729_00.JPG" alt="Small Coffee Shop in Chazawa-dori">
Small shops like this (in this case a coffee shop) are the reason I love Japan so much. Just look at all the details!</p>
<p><img src="/images/japan03/2023-04-30_133035_00.JPG" alt="Entrance to Shimokitazawa">
At the end of Chazawa-dori, you can find Shimokitazawa, a very popular area that gained a lot of popularity since I first visited Japan in 2014. This area is known for second hand clothing and furniture and also has a lot of restaurants. As you can see, it was packed! Everyone was using their day off to do a bit of shopping and catch up with friends.</p>
<p><img src="/images/japan03/2023-04-30_150211_00.JPG" alt="Playing Shogi in the streets">
There was a tournament of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shogi">Shogi</a> (also called Japanese Chess) held in the streets. It was quite interesting to watch. Bystanders were very engaged with every move the players did.</p>
<p><img src="/images/japan03/2023-04-30_150538_00.JPG" alt="Front door with technology and beautiful decay">
Beautiful mess of colors, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wabi-sabi">Wabisabi</a> (beautiful decay) and technology.</p>
<p><img src="/images/japan03/2023-04-30_182803_00.JPG" alt="Wooden House in modern City">
This traditional japanese wooden house is close to our hotel and stands in stark contrast to the rest of the surrounding, which is super modern.</p>

    ]]>
      </content>
    </entry>
  
    
    <entry>
      <title>To the Japanese Alps</title>
      <link href="https://jonas.place/posts/to-the-japanese-alps/"/>
      <updated>2023-05-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <id>https://jonas.place/posts/to-the-japanese-alps/</id>
      <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[
      <p><img src="/images/japan04/2023-05-01_073306_00.JPG" alt="View from our hotel window">
View from our hotel window in the morning</p>
<p>Today, we woke up early at around 7:30 AM and left for Shinjuku Station to reach our next destination: The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Japanese_Alps">Japanese Alps</a>. We got up so early in fact, that we had an hour to waste at Shinjuku Station. After looking for a Bento (Lunchbox) but failing to find one, we decided to go to the only(!) Café, we could see in the vicinity. The food was okay, nothing to write home about. Then we checked out our train - and found Bento!
It was being sold directly on the platform of our departure. Pretty convenient. (Later I found out, that all the rest of the shops and restaurants were on a completely different floor of the station… Japan, you can be confusing at times.)</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Check out an interactive Map of the places we visited <a href="https://wanderlog.com/view/ipgoeoyijw/japan-trip/shared">here</a>. I will update this map as we continue our Journey. This post is about Day 4.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><img src="/images/japan04/2023-05-01_093107_00.JPG" alt="Drinks in Train form">
The Bento-Shop sold Drinks in the form of little Trains, why not?</p>
<p>Our train left Shinjuku punctually at 10 AM sharp – and we were off. The weather was nice, the train was spotless, the Wi-Fi on the train worked. Everything was dandy!</p>
<p><img src="/images/japan04/2023-05-01_111309_00.JPG" alt="Image of Bento on a Train">
After about 2 hours of riding the train, I decided to crack open my Bento box. It was underwhelmingly bland but did the job of making me less hungry.</p>
<p>This is also, where things went south. There was a signal disturbance that affected our train. We had to make an impromptu stop and then nothing happened for about 1:30 hours. Except for the train clerk anouncing over and over again that they were sorry and that there was a problem with the signal and that they are working to fix it and that it would probably be fixed soon.</p>
<p>We reached our transfer station just one minute late for us to catch our connecting train to our destination. So we had to wait another hour. So all in all, I had a lot of time to think about and observe the behaviour of people. Some things I noted were:</p>
<ul>
<li>Japanese people don't wear sunglasses (Of course some do but surprisingly little. During our trip I saw 2 Japanese people out of maybe 100 that would wear sunglasses and - as said - it was a sunny day today)</li>
<li>On our route, there was very little renewable energy and thinking back, I never noticed wind power in all my travels in Japan. Also, there was only one solar park on the whole route from Tokyo to the Japanese Alps.</li>
<li>People traveling to the Japanese Alps are serious about hiking. Most people wore functional clothes, hiking boots, some even walking/hiking sticks, even though the terrain in the Japanese alps is easy to moderate compared to most hiking routes in Austria/Switzerland/Norway…</li>
<li>There are amazing restrooms everywhere but most of them don't have soap in them. So prepare to bring your own sanitizer!</li>
</ul>
<p><img src="/images/japan04/2023-05-01_162426_00.JPG" alt="image">
At 3:45 PM, we reached our destination: Narai-Juku! A post-town in the Japanese Alps. These towns were laying on the route of the post transports between Kyoto and Tokyo. A few hundred years later, a lot of the houses are still pretty well kept and people still actually still work an live here – mostly in the tourism industry of course.</p>
<p>We checked into our Minshuku (Guest House) shortly after arriving. It is located right in the town center with very pretty houses all around!</p>
<p>We walked around in Narai-Juku and found some cute shops. We had such a lovely &quot;talk&quot; (we tried to communicate in all the ways possible) with an elderly lady that sold us handmade postcards that her deceased husband made (they were 1€ each). Encounters like this make the trip to Japan completely worth it!
<img src="/images/japan04/2023-05-01_165947_00.JPG" alt="image">
At 5PM, most of the shops close and thus, most of the people leave Narai-Juku. Finally, we could take some pictures without people in them!
<img src="/images/japan04/2023-05-01_170440_00.JPG" alt="image">
I didn't realise, that cars could also pass through this ancient town which kind of &quot;ruins the vibe&quot; but I guess it's necessary since this town is still actively lived in and not only a backdrop for pretty pictures.
<img src="/images/japan04/2023-05-01_172200_00.JPG" alt="image">
Anyway, here's the last picture of pretty houses (for today).
<img src="/images/japan04/2023-05-01_180155_00.JPG" alt="image">
At 6 PM it was dinner time. I was pretty hungry before so I had a few nuts.</p>
<p>The dinner started with just a few plates, pictured above. Our host gave us only this much information about the proceedings of the evening: &quot;Dinner is served between 6 PM and 7:15 PM&quot;. I thought: Good, that I ate some nuts before since this is not much at all! Next, our host brought out boiled vegetables that we could dip into a sauce that he prepared. Pretty nice but I was still hungry, I ate two bowls of rice with that. There were a lot more courses to follow after that though:</p>
<ul>
<li>Clam chowder</li>
<li>Grilled Trout</li>
<li>Horse Sashimi (delicious with garlic sauce!)</li>
<li>Tempura</li>
<li>Miso Soup</li>
<li>Fruits</li>
<li>Ice cream</li>
</ul>
<p>I left about 2kg heavier than before. Everything was delicious, prepared with care and served with love. I was happily surprised!
<img src="/images/japan04/2023-05-01_161343_00.JPG" alt="image">
We finished the evening by going to the bath in the Guest House which was reserved especially for us! It was a Japanese Sento: A bath were you wash yourself before resting in the hot water (thermal bath). It is soo relaxing to feel the warmth on your tired muscles.</p>
<p>Aparently, in Japan, my name is Mr. Jonas.</p>

    ]]>
      </content>
    </entry>
  
    
    <entry>
      <title>Hiking the Nakasendo</title>
      <link href="https://jonas.place/posts/hiking-the-nakasendo/"/>
      <updated>2023-05-02T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <id>https://jonas.place/posts/hiking-the-nakasendo/</id>
      <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[
      <p>We  left our Minshuku without breakfast to hurry to the Narai Train Station at 8:30 AM. There was only one train leaving at 8:40 AM and the next one was leaving at after 11 AM. Luckily, we got our train and rode it for 1:30 hours to Nagiso. From there, the hiking started.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Check out an interactive Map of the places we visited <a href="https://wanderlog.com/view/ipgoeoyijw/japan-trip/shared">here</a>. I will update this map as we continue our Journey. This post is about Day 5.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The Nakasendo is the path connecting the post towns and you can &quot;hike&quot; it. Most of the path is paved or has cobblestones on it. There are some steep sections though but nothing that warrants the use of special hiking gear.</p>
<p><img src="/images/japan05/2023-05-02_113201_00.JPG" alt="Tsumago Juku">
After about 45 minutes of hiking, we reached Tsumago-Juku. This Post Town looks a lot like Narai but has a lot more greenery both inside the town and surrounding it. <s>Even though it is Golden Week right now, there were not that many tourists, as you can see yourself in this picture (it was taken at 11:30 AM).</s></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Correction: It totally wasn't golden week as we found out one day later. Golden week started at 3rd of May 2023 and the Post Towns got significantly more crowded.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>We had some snacks in Tsumago and continued our hike in the direction of Magome Juku, the last post town along our Journey.
<img src="/images/japan05/2023-05-02_122118_00.JPG" alt="Nakasendo">
Most of the Nakasendo looks exactly like this. Not too hard to hike on, well structured with big signs guiding you along the way.</p>
<p>Other things to note about the Nakasendo:</p>
<ul>
<li>There are public toilets every 500 Metres along the Nakasendo! They were clean but none had any soap.</li>
<li>People live along the hiking trail in beautiful villages/single homes with pretty gardens.</li>
<li>The scenery changes constantly: from forests to clearings to hills to settlements… It does not get boring at all. There were some parts where we had to hike alongside a road because part of the hiking trail were closed though.</li>
<li>If you don't want to hike but still want to visit the towns, you can just go by car/bus/train and still see most of the beauty that the Nakasendo has to offer (and be much less sweaty for it).</li>
</ul>
<p><img src="/images/japan05/2023-05-02_143223_00.JPG" alt="Beware of bears on the Nakasendo">
There is one challenge though: The Nakasendo is in bear territory. Signs are warning you constantly about possible encounters with bears. To keep bears at bay, you should create lots of noises. Luckily, the Nakasendo is equipped with lots of bells that you should ring when passing by to warn the bears about your arrival.
<img src="/images/japan05/2023-05-02_133755_00.JPG" alt="Tea kettle">
At about the halfway point between Tsumago and Magome, there is a tea house which serves free tea. The tea is boiled in this kettle over an open flame.
<img src="/images/japan05/2023-05-02_142630_00.JPG" alt="Garden Image">
Just after reaching the outskirts of Magome, we found this private garden of a local who invited us to have a look. It was quite chaotic and cluttered but beautiful in its own way. I like this Maple tree in front of the small pond (which had chairs and tables in it for some reason).
<img src="/images/japan05/2023-05-02_144837_00.JPG" alt="Lookout point before Magome">
There was a lookout point just before entering the town that is Magome Juku. In the background, you can see some of the lower Japanese Alps.
<img src="/images/japan05/2023-05-02_161917_00.JPG" alt="Flowers in front of a shop in Magome Juku">
In Magome Juku (but also along the whole Nakasendo), there were a lot of beautiful flowers that were just in bloom here. Compared to Tokyo, where Spring is almost over, the colder climate of the Japanese Alps makes for a later bloom of flowers, comparable to the time they bloom in northern Germany.
<img src="/images/japan05/2023-05-02_161209_00.JPG" alt="Gohei Mochi in a shop in the sun">
After arriving in Magome, we checked into our hotel, got some rest and then explored the town more. We found a shop which sells this type of Mochi called Gohei Mochi (there are many shops like this on the Nakasendo but this is one of them). These are delicious. Compared to other types of Mochi, which are completely smooth inside, this type of mochi has some rice particles still left intact. Thus it has a less doughy type of texture. The sauce was the king of the show and tastes sweet and savory at the same time, similar to Dango. Also similar to dango, Gohei Mochi is grilled over an open flame.
<img src="/images/japan05/2023-05-02_181021_00.JPG" alt="Magome Juku empty">
After 6 PM, most of the people left Magome Juku and we could take some picture like that. Tough I think this is the last picture of post town for this journey.</p>
<p>In summary:<br>
It was a pretty uneventful day. We hiked a lot, had lots of snacks along the way and saw amazingly beautiful scenery. Sadly, this beauty does not translate that well into pictures (or I am just a bad photographer) but I am not so happy with the pictures I got from today. As beautiful as the post towns are, there are only so many pictures you can take of them without getting bored.</p>

    ]]>
      </content>
    </entry>
  
    
    <entry>
      <title>Relaxing in the Japanese Countryside</title>
      <link href="https://jonas.place/posts/relaxing-in-the-japanese-countryside/"/>
      <updated>2023-05-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <id>https://jonas.place/posts/relaxing-in-the-japanese-countryside/</id>
      <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[
      <p>This post is about the last two days of our journey in Japan. On day 6, we spent the rest of the day in Magome and then travelled to the Japanese countryside. Today (day 7), we just relaxed a lot.</p>
<h1>Day 6 - Magome</h1>
<p>Yesterday, we started the day in Magome-Juku. The original plan was to catch a bus in the next larger city, Nakatsugawa and then go to the countryside from there. But as we realised, this bus also goes through Magome-Juku… So we rebooked the bus from Magome-Juku leaving at 3 PM. So we had to pass the day in Magome somehow. We had a great coffee at <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/HillBilly+Coffee+Company/@35.5251473,137.5631691,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m6!3m5!1s0x601cb6fd476935ed:0x5b18e4a4d4bb7679!8m2!3d35.525143!4d137.565744!16s%2Fg%2F11dxsvnwbn">Hillbilly Coffe</a> (an actual Hipster Coffee Place in a historic town… how great is that?) which served me one of the best cappucinos I ever had.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Check out an interactive Map of the places we visited <a href="https://wanderlog.com/view/ipgoeoyijw/japan-trip/shared">here</a>. I will update this map as we continue our Journey. This post is about Day 6 and 7.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><img src="/images/japan07/2023-05-03_134013_00.JPG" alt="Overcrowded Magome-Juku">
Compared to the days before, there were a lot more people in the Magome-Juku. This is, because Golden Week started on the 3rd of May (I was wrongly writing that it started prior to that). With that many people, Magome-Juku was a lot less fun.<br>
By the way, the blue thing you see in the picture above (left side of the picture) is some kind of Pokémon Go Stop. The whole town of Magome had signs for Pokémon Go which kind of ruined the quaint vibe a bit.
<img src="/images/japan07/2023-05-03_105740_00.JPG" alt="Magome Juku the non-touristy parts">
So we decided to check out the parts of Magome-Juku that were not overrun by tourists. Just by leaving the main street and walking 200 Metres, you end up in places like this were you cannot see a tourist at all. Pretty nice!
<img src="/images/japan07/2023-05-03_105935_00.JPG" alt="This is a bus stop in Magome-Juku">
By the way: This is a bus stop in Magome-Juku!
<img src="/images/japan07/2023-05-03_135552_00.JPG" alt="Dogs with hats">
There were a lot of people with dogs in Magome-Juku and they were all wearing some kind of costume or hats… I don't know what that was about but it was quite fun.</p>
<p>We had a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kaiseki">Kaiseki</a>-Lunch at one of the best Japanese Restaurants I ever set foot in in Magome-Juku, <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/Haginoya/@35.5239346,137.5650787,20.88z/data=!4m14!1m7!3m6!1s0x601cb6fd476935ed:0x5b18e4a4d4bb7679!2sHillBilly+Coffee+Company!8m2!3d35.525143!4d137.565744!16s%2Fg%2F11dxsvnwbn!3m5!1s0x601cb6e2c93ad075:0x312a253ac85c0bd2!8m2!3d35.5238588!4d137.5653563!16s%2Fg%2F1ttpgzj2">Haginoya</a>. We were seated in a private room and were served five courses. Everyting was sourced locally and tasted great (I'll spare you the details of each course). And at the end we paid around 5000 yen for two people which is equivalent to around 34 €. Amazing deal for the money!</p>
<p>We caught the bus, which took us to Sawando where we had booked the Airbnb for the night.
<img src="/images/japan07/2023-05-03_164234_00.JPG" alt="Shrine in the Mountain">
After about 1.5 hours, we arrived in Sawando. The town of Sawando is nothing special. A bit of industry, some restaurants and a highway to the towns nearby. We walked 15 Minutes from the bus stop to our Airbnb which was a bit up the hill and away from the busyness of the road and the town. The image above captures the spirit of the way to the Airbnb.</p>
<p>We checked into the Airbnb and walked back to Sawando Center to grab Dinner.</p>
<h1>Day 7 – Sawando</h1>
<p>We relaxed a lot today.</p>
<p><img src="/images/japan07/2023-05-04_125233_00.JPG" alt="Garden of Airbnb">
The cottage that we stayed in was in a beautiful garden. There even was a tiny pond where some frogs live. We could hear the frogs croaking at night which was relaxing.
<img src="/images/japan07/2023-05-04_083101_00.JPG" alt="View of the Cottage">
The Airbnb was very small but big enough for two people two comfortably live/sleep in. It was so nice to wake up and see a surrounding like this.
<img src="/images/japan07/2023-05-04_084424_00.JPG" alt="Industrial area">
In the morning, I went to a 7-Eleven in Sawando to get breakfast – Pancakes with maple Syrup and Mini Croissants. Sawando does not offer great sights and so I took pictures of the everyday life of a small town in Japan. Here you can see the entrance of an industrial builduing close to the 7-Eleven that I walked to.
<img src="/images/japan07/2023-05-04_090557_00.JPG" alt="The way up the mountain to our Airbnb">
The way up the mountain to the Airbnb looks like this and is just so lovely.
<img src="/images/japan07/2023-05-04_113949_00.jpg" alt="Momo-Chan">
The Airbnb we stayed at has a Shiba Inu Dog called Momo-Chan. At noon, we took Momo-Chan on a walk to a café nearby. She behaved amazingly well for being on a walk with us for the first time. I just love her friendly face!
<img src="/images/japan07/2023-05-04_120827_00.JPG" alt="Abandoned Truck">
In the japanese countryside, you can find a lot of abandoned buildings and vehicles. They can make for some pretty interesting shots like the one above.
<img src="/images/japan07/2023-05-04_121544_00.JPG" alt="Mountainscape in Sawando">
The mountainscape of the Japanese Alps around Sawando is very nice to look at.
<img src="/images/japan07/2023-05-04_121731_00.JPG" alt="Small Shop">
We passed by a small shop on our way back from the walk and saw this small shop which sold snacks. The owner, an elderly woman tried to communicate somewhat successfully but couldn't get her point accros. She fetched her daughter who is an English teacher to translate. Daughter and Mother don't see many tourists. Sawando is not in any guide books and does not have any (!) hotels. Both daughter and mother were totally sweet. The daughter is also an artist and showed us her pastel paintings. We bought some postcards to send back to Germany.
<img src="/images/japan07/2023-05-04_122142_00.JPG" alt="Detail in Sawando with Mirror">
Some flowers in a window and a mirror in front of the shop described above.</p>
<p>And… that was pretty much the seventh day in Japan. Other than that we washed our clothes, organised stuff, called back home and enjoyed the sunlight and the warmth that the countryside has to offer.</p>
<p>Tomorrow will be an interesting day as we will travel about 6 hours in total with 5 differrent trains to reach the next destination which is also in a Japanese village but even more remote than Sawando.<br>
The things you do to avoid the masses of tourists at Golden Week…</p>

    ]]>
      </content>
    </entry>
  
    
    <entry>
      <title>A day spent in trains</title>
      <link href="https://jonas.place/posts/a-day-spent-in-trains/"/>
      <updated>2023-05-05T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <id>https://jonas.place/posts/a-day-spent-in-trains/</id>
      <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[
      <p>We spent the day today traveling. We took the first train at 8:12 AM and reached our accomodation at 3:15 PM. So in total, we travelled over 7 hours. It was pretty warm as well with 26° C and a lot of local trains were not air conditioned. So it was an exhausting day and not many pictures were taken.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Check out an interactive Map of the places we visited <a href="https://wanderlog.com/view/ipgoeoyijw/japan-trip/shared">here</a>. I will update this map as we continue our Journey. This post is about Day 8.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Our destination today were the historic villages of Gokayama. The traditional houses there make up for some pretty unique sights. They are built in a particular style called <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Minka">Gassho-Zukuri</a>. We made the choice to go to this remote location to avoid the big crowds of Golden week in major touristic hotspots.</p>
<p><img src="/images/japan08/2023-05-05_120027_00.jpg" alt="View of Japanese Alps">
We took ALL the trains (plus a bus at the end). From the slow local trains that stop everywhere to the Shinkansen that reaches top speeds of over 200 km/h there was a nice variety. The views of the Japanese Alps were pretty spectacular as you can see above.</p>
<p>One thing we learned today: Taking trains during golden week is <em>fine</em>. They can get crowded which can be a bit unpleasant but it is not as bad as I would have thought. Sometimes you have to stand for a couple of minutes before a seat becomes available and that's about the most uncomfotable it gets.
<img src="/images/japan08/2023-05-05_144232_00.jpg" alt="Earthquake alert">
When reaching Gokayama, all the phones in the bus were sounding an alarm for an earthquake that would have &quot;strong shaking&quot;. The sound of the alarm startled me. I asked myself what I should do with the information to best prepare myself for &quot;strong shaking&quot; but I couldn't think of anything. A couple seconds later, there was a mild shifting back and forth (like a bus usually does anyway  ) and that was it. Later that day, there was another alert in the accomodation and this one was a bit more noticeable. But all in all I am pretty excited that after 3 trips in Japan, I finally experienced an earthquake!
<img src="/images/japan08/2023-05-05_145344_00.jpg" alt="Gassho-Zukuri Houses at the Entrance of Kaminashi">
When we got out at our bus stop, we already saw some Gassho-Zukuri style houses at the entrance of our village that we stayed in for the night.</p>
<p>The following two images show the surroundings of the village. Yeah, it is pretty remote!
<img src="/images/japan08/2023-05-05_145906_00.jpg" alt="Village with river">
<img src="/images/japan08/2023-05-05_150630_00.jpg" alt="Remote location with road">
When we finally arrived at the accomodation, we just laid on the floor for an hour or so. We ate dinner and played some cards and called it a day.</p>

    ]]>
      </content>
    </entry>
  
    
    <entry>
      <title>Gokayama</title>
      <link href="https://jonas.place/posts/gokayama/"/>
      <updated>2023-05-06T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <id>https://jonas.place/posts/gokayama/</id>
      <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[
      <p>Today, we checked out the UNESCO World heritage site that is Gokayama. We went to the village of Ainokura where we saw traditional <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Minka">Gassho-Zukuri</a>-houses. It was a relaxed day at the countryside.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Check out an interactive Map of the places we visited <a href="https://wanderlog.com/view/ipgoeoyijw/japan-trip/shared">here</a>. I will update this map as we continue our Journey. This post is about Day 9.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><img src="/images/japan09/2023-05-06_091834_00.jpg" alt="Exile house">
Small house in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Minka">Gassho-Zukuri</a> style that was used as an exile house for people that misbehaved in the village to expel them from the community. This hut is the only exile hut remaining in Japan, it is just a replica though.
<img src="/images/japan09/2023-05-06_093031_00.JPG" alt="Inside the Gassho-Zukuri house">
We also visitied a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Minka">Gassho-Zukuri</a> house and saw the insides of it. These houses are quite spacious but they also had to fulfill a lot of functions. This is what we learned about the house that we visited:</p>
<ul>
<li>It housed more than 20 people.</li>
<li>It was used to keep cattle as well as people.</li>
<li>The upper floor was used to house Silk Moth Caterpillars to make traditional Japanese clothes from.</li>
<li>The steep angle of the roof was useful to keep masses of snow from collapsing the house.</li>
<li>All the houses were built without a single nail.</li>
</ul>
<p><img src="/images/japan09/2023-05-06_112732_00.JPG" alt="Gassho-Zukuri House in Ainokura">
We walked to Ainokura, which is one of three Gokayama villages that you can visit. Ainokura is medium-sized compared to the other two villages. It has about 20 <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Minka">Gassho-Zukuri</a> houses in total. In some of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Minka">Gassho-Zukuri</a> houses in Ainokura, people are actually still living in. Some houses are used as accomodations for tourists, others are used as museums or restaurants.
<img src="/images/japan09/2023-05-06_105746_00.jpg" alt="Mountain Panorama in Ainokura">
There are not only <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Minka">Gassho-Zukuri</a> houses in Ainokura. It also has other, non-historic buildings like the one pictured above. As you can see, the surrounding mountains make up for a beautiful backdrop of the whole village.
<img src="/images/japan09/2023-05-06_115409_00.JPG" alt="Ainokura View">
There is one particular photo-spot in Ainokura, that you <em>have</em> to go to and it is <a href="https://www.google.de/maps/place/Ainokura+Panoramic+Viewpoint/@36.4277733,136.9317984,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m6!3m5!1s0x5ff817ad533e09c7:0xa38c22e844c1d5d4!8m2!3d36.427769!4d136.9343733!16s%2Fg%2F11f9z0hsx6">this one</a>. Of course, we went there and took the picture above.
<img src="/images/japan09/2023-05-06_125909_00.JPG" alt="Road back home with bent road boundaries">
We spent about 2 hours in Ainokura (we also had some small coffee and ice cream there) and then went back to our accomodation. The way back is paved but no cars are allowed on this road. I loved these three road boundaries that get increasingly more bent from left to right.
<img src="/images/japan09/2023-05-06_141238_00.JPG" alt="Wild Wisteria growing close to a river">
In all of Japan, you can see a lot of wild Wisteria growing and hanging from trees. Right now, they are in bloom in the regions we travelled to which is always a beautiful sight.
<img src="/images/japan09/2023-05-06_141948_00.JPG" alt="Sign leading you to our hostel">
The place we stayed at is quite remote. Luckily, there is a sign on the road, guiding you the correct way. Otherwise it's kind of irritating to walk on a country road without any pedestrian walkway in the middle of nowhere.</p>

    ]]>
      </content>
    </entry>
  
    
    <entry>
      <title>Kanazawa, Part I</title>
      <link href="https://jonas.place/posts/kanazawa-part-i/"/>
      <updated>2023-05-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <id>https://jonas.place/posts/kanazawa-part-i/</id>
      <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[
      <p>Golden week is finally over! It's time to go back to the tourist hotspots. Our first hotspot is Kanazawa. A city that I did not know that much about. Apparently, before and during the Edo Period, this city was pretty rich and thus has a lot of very interesting sights to see!</p>
<p>Kanazawa is called the Seattle of Japan (because of a lot of rain/wind) and today, it gave us exactly that: A lot of rain. The rain didn't even stop for one second.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Check out an interactive Map of the places we visited <a href="https://wanderlog.com/view/ipgoeoyijw/japan-trip/shared">here</a>. I will update this map as we continue our Journey. This post is about Day 10.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><img src="/images/japan10/2023-05-07_103004_00.JPG" alt="Mountains in fog">
In the morning, we left Gokayama by Highway Bus. The mountains were foggy and looked mysterious.</p>
<p>We reached Kanazawa around noon which was too early to check into our Airbnb. That's why we took some time to explore the city on foot. Kanazawa is not that big and so it does not take long to walk from the central station to pretty much all touristy spots.
<img src="/images/japan10/2023-05-07_125143_00.JPG" alt="Wine bar">
If you are into western-style bars/cafés/restaurants, you are in for a treat in Kanazawa. There are so many cute and interesting places that have a pretty western style. Esther was reminded of the UK with some places. The picture above shows a wine bar. I love how the ivy gives the building a lot of character.
<img src="/images/japan10/2023-05-07_132802_00.jpg" alt="Back-alley with green and beer crates">
Kanazawa is extremely green. One upside of having a lot of precipitation, I guess.
<img src="/images/japan10/2023-05-07_133532_00.JPG" alt="Samurai District front yard">
After about 15 minutes of walking, we reached the Samurai District, Nagamachi. In this district, a lot of the historical places where the Samurai (the highest cast of the ancient Japanese society) lived.
<img src="/images/japan10/2023-05-07_133827_00.JPG" alt="Alley in Nagamachi, the samurai district">
The rain made for some interesting views of this district. Not a lot of people where around and Esther and me were in photography heaven. We took so many pictures.
<img src="/images/japan10/2023-05-07_143556_00.jpg" alt="Fishes in a Samurai House">
We also visited a traditional Samurai house, Nomura-ke. In contrast to a lot of the Samurai-houses in Japan, this one was still in the state it was in, when the Samurai lived in it. The garden of the house was extremely beautiful with Koi fishes, a waterfall, lots of pretty plants and so on. We partook in a tea ceremony which was just wonderful in this setting.
<img src="/images/japan10/2023-05-07_145319_00.JPG" alt="Modern architecture in Kanazawa">
Kanazawa also has some interesting modern architecture. In this shot, I like the reflection of the surfaces that reflect back light from different directions.
<img src="/images/japan10/2023-05-07_145914_00.jpg" alt="Pink staircase">
This pink monochrome staircase is very mesmerizing. It just appeared out of nowhere and caught my attention immediately.
<img src="/images/japan10/2023-05-07_150244_00.JPG" alt="Beautiful Mess in a back-alley">
In contrast to the very organized and clean look, that a lot of old and new buildings in Japan have, there is also this completely messy side of Japan. Those electricity metres, combined with the umbrella and random wires sticking out of the wall are something that I am not used to see in Germany.
<img src="/images/japan10/2023-05-07_183712_00.JPG" alt="Heavy rainfall">
The rainfall got worse and worse over time. Our shoes were getting wetter and wetter. Luckily, we bought umbrellas earlier so the rest of our clothes were fine.
<img src="/images/japan10/2023-05-07_183819_00.JPG" alt="image">
<img src="/images/japan10/2023-05-07_192712_00.JPG" alt="image"></p>

    ]]>
      </content>
    </entry>
  
    
    <entry>
      <title>Kanazawa, then Kyoto</title>
      <link href="https://jonas.place/posts/kanazawa-then-kyoto/"/>
      <updated>2023-05-09T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <id>https://jonas.place/posts/kanazawa-then-kyoto/</id>
      <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[
      <p>I will do my best to summarize the last 48 hours. We spent half a day in Kanazawa. After about 24 hours in Kanazawa, we felt that we had seen all that there was to see in Kanazawa. Then we left Kanazawa and went to Kyoto. There, we were mesmerized by the beauty of the city, the friendliness of Japanese people and just <em>how many tourists can fit in one city</em> (It's way more tourists than we saw during Golden Week).</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Check out an interactive Map of the places we visited <a href="https://wanderlog.com/view/ipgoeoyijw/japan-trip/shared">here</a>. I will update this map as we continue our Journey. This post is about Day 11 and 12.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I will split this entry in two sections: The rest of our Kanazawa-Trip and the beginning of our time in Kyoto.</p>
<h1>Kanazawa</h1>
<p>We got up semi-early to see the Geisha-District that was just around the corner of our Airbnb. It was not crowded at all on a Monday morning at 9 AM and we felt as if we had the streets to ourselves. The following three pictures should show that vibe.
<img src="/images/japan11/2023-05-08_085948_00.JPG" alt="Impression of ancient Geisha District of Kanazawa">
<img src="/images/japan11/2023-05-08_090813_00.JPG" alt="Impression of ancient Geisha District of Kanazawa">
<img src="/images/japan11/2023-05-08_091327_00.JPG" alt="Impression of ancient Geisha District of Kanazawa"></p>
<p>Since Golden Week was finally officially over and the Post Offices were open again, we bought a lot of postage Stamps and sent out all the postcards we failed to send out in the days before. Postage is comparably cheap in Japan. To send a postcard from Japan to Germany via priority Mail, it costs only 70 ¥ which is less than 0.5 €. That is cheaper than sending a postcard within Germany!</p>
<p><img src="/images/japan11/2023-05-08_105119_00.jpg" alt="Traffic Light in Kanazawa">
One curious thing in Kanazawa is, that all pedestrian traffic lights have a small speaker that is mounted on a pole that extends to the side of the traffic light. All traffic lights in Japan do have speakers to signal to visually impaired people when the light is green but to see those speakers mounted to the side looked funny to me.</p>
<p>We also went to the Kenrokuen-Garden (it was not as amazing as all the guides were trying to sell it as) and tried very hard to find a place to eat lunch. A lot of places were closed even though they should have been open (Google Maps said so). The reason being that Golden Week was over and shop-owners were having breaks from the business.</p>
<h1>Kyoto</h1>
<p>We took the train to Kyoto around 3pm and reached it right before sunset.
<img src="/images/japan11/2023-05-08_182752_00.jpg" alt="Impression of Kyoto at Sunset">
Kyoto has a grid like layout of streets and is comparably flat (even though it is surrounded by mountains on three sides), so shots like this are possible on a lot of streets.</p>
<p>In the evening, we went to a Okonomiyaki-Restaurant (Japanese Pancake). It was delicious! Later, we checked out the bar-scene in Kyoto.</p>
<p>We found one very nice place which had a live DJ that played funk records from the 60s and 70s and had a very &quot;homey&quot;-vibe. The place already closed at 10:30 PM and we got to talk to the DJ once all the other guests left. He recommended us a place nearby: A Jazz-Bar where you can drink a good Whisky Sour.
<img src="/images/japan11/2023-05-08_221000_00.JPG" alt="Impression of Jazz-Bar">
As you can see, there was a certain chaos in this Jazz-Bar. We got to talk to a lot of interesting people and tried the Whisky Sour which was not a Whisky Sour at all. It was pretty chaotic but a lot of fun!
<img src="/images/japan11/2023-05-08_220750_00.JPG" alt="Impression of Jazz-Bar">
Maybe it was even too much fun since I couldn't get out of bed on the next day.  I left our hotel at around 2 PM.</p>
<p><img src="/images/japan11/2023-05-09_141234_00.jpg" alt="image">
The weather was fantastic. We rented bikes and went northwards. Kyoto is surrounded by mountains and the more you move away from the city-center, the more village-like Kyoto becomes and the more interesting shops and places you can see (in my opinion).
<img src="/images/japan11/2023-05-09_150923_00.jpg" alt="Cafe">
We found a cute Café, had a very late breakfast and enjoyed the beautiful surroundings and weather.</p>
<p>I found out that eating was a good idea but this café just could not satisfy my appetite for a hearty meal.
<img src="/images/japan11/2023-05-09_155923_00.JPG" alt="Menu of Gyoza-Restaurant">
Ever since going to Japan, we wanted to go to a dedicated Gyoza-Restaurant. We found such a place easily accessible by bike in Kyoto. This place looked like it hadn't been renovated since opening around 30 years ago. The walls could tell stories, the menu was just available in Japanese (as you can see in the picture above) and the waitress/owner (?) didn't speak much English.
<img src="/images/japan11/2023-05-09_155833_00.JPG" alt="Gyoza-Restaurant">
<img src="/images/japan11/2023-05-09_160518_00.JPG" alt="Gyoza">
I ordered a cheap Gyoza-Menu and was happy!</p>
<p>After having satisfied our hunger, we explored further on our bikes and found a very pretty shrine - Kitano Tenman-gū that was not crowded at all. The following pictures show a few impressions from that shrine.
<img src="/images/japan11/2023-05-09_164648_00.jpg" alt="Shrine Impression">
Those are wishes that you can write on wooden slates. This shrine had so many wishes that you couldn't even see the underlying structure anymore.
<img src="/images/japan11/2023-05-09_164854_00.JPG" alt="Shrine Impression">
<img src="/images/japan11/2023-05-09_183653_00.JPG" alt="Sunset close to Kyomizu-Dera">
We wanted to finish the day with a sunset shot of Kyomizu-Dera but unfortunately, it closed at 6 PM (even though I checked on Google Maps and didn't find any information on opening hours). So you just have to live with this picture of Gion (the surrounding Area of Kyomizu-Dera).</p>

    ]]>
      </content>
    </entry>
  
    
    <entry>
      <title>What we have been up to in the last few days</title>
      <link href="https://jonas.place/posts/what-we-have-been-up-to-in-the-last-few-days/"/>
      <updated>2023-05-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <id>https://jonas.place/posts/what-we-have-been-up-to-in-the-last-few-days/</id>
      <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[
      <p>Things got a bit overwhelming in the last few days. Spending time in cities is awesome but also comes with the drawback of not having any free time in the evenings because there is so much going on. We had two more lovely days in Kyoto then went to Osaka and Tokushima. Now we are back in the countryside, this time we are in Shikoku, Japan's smallest and least touristy main island!</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Check out an interactive Map of the places we visited <a href="https://wanderlog.com/view/ipgoeoyijw/japan-trip/shared">here</a>. I will update this map as we continue our Journey. This post is about Day 13 to 16.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I split this entry in the cities we visited.</p>
<h1>Kyoto</h1>
<p>Kyoto was super lovely to us! With the bikes we rented, we cycled around Kyoto like there was no tomorrow. In total, we cycled about 45 km in two days…
<img src="/images/japan16/2023-05-10_143551_00.JPG" alt="image">
This were our bikes! Just look at those tiny tires. Aren't they lovely? I always wanted to ride such a bike and after spending a couple hours on one I must admit that they are pretty comfortable to ride on and also pretty speedy. They were plenty fast enough for cruising around Kyoto and super easy to park anywhere (It is very hard to find good/free bicycle parking in Kyoto for some reason).</p>
<p>By the way, in the picture above, the bikes are &quot;locked&quot;. See for yourself if you can find this totally insecure &quot;locking&quot; mechanism that we were instructed to use.</p>
<p>The following pictures are just some random impressions that I got while cycling around.
<img src="/images/japan16/2023-05-10_114822_00.JPG" alt="image">
Somehow, you constantly cross train tracks in Kyoto when cycling. A lot of train tracks are built right on the roadside level (compared to Tokyo and Osaka where Trains are either underground or above ground). With the train schedule of a bustling city like Kyoto, you will be sure to wait at one of those Train crossings more often than not.
<img src="/images/japan16/2023-05-10_122317_00.JPG" alt="image">
Pretty architecture we found close to the museum quarter of Kyoto.
<img src="/images/japan16/2023-05-10_131512_00.JPG" alt="image">
This picture and the following one were taken at Nanzen-Ji. One of my favorite gardens in the whole of Japan. Super quiet, quite small and very pretty. It has a waterfall, a pond with Kois, some bridges and a whole lot more.
<img src="/images/japan16/2023-05-10_131632_00.JPG" alt="image">
<img src="/images/japan16/2023-05-10_143716_00.JPG" alt="image">
This is Japan too: Sights like these are very common: Trash being collected at the side of the road. Each type of trash has its own day where it is collected.
<img src="/images/japan16/2023-05-10_155410_00.JPG" alt="image">
This was one of the biggest disappointments of our trip to Kyoto. After an exhaustingly hot day, we cycled to this spot: The Kyoto international conference center. I got the idea to go there from a guide-book which listed this building in the top 5 architectural sights in Kyoto. When arriving there, we found out that you cannot enter the building without a permit so the only pictures I could take were from the front of the building which was impressive but didn't blow me away. After about 10 Minutes of shooting pictures, a guard came out and signaled us to leave the premises.
<img src="/images/japan16/2023-05-11_123224_00.JPG" alt="image">
On our last (half) day in Kyoto, we went to two touristy hot-spots. Monkey Park (see above) and Bamboo forest…
<img src="/images/japan16/2023-05-11_123617_00.JPG" alt="image">
This picture of a monkey in front of security camera screens was just funny to me somehow.
<img src="/images/japan16/2023-05-11_131359_00.JPG" alt="image">
Imagine lots of Bamboos standing next to each other. Now imagine lots of people walking next to this bamboo. Got that? Okay, you know what Bamboo forest is like.</p>
<h1>Osaka</h1>
<p>We left Kyoto at around 4 PM and arrived in Osaka at around 5 PM (there are local trains that run from one city to the other constantly). When we arrived in Osaka, it was already kind of late and we had to pick up a car on the next morning at 12 PM so there was not much time to explore this huge city!</p>
<p>We had Kushikatsu (Fried Stuff on Skewers), tried the famous cake of Rikuro that is so popular around the internet (We were not impressed. This cake is no match for almost any cake in German Cafés).
<img src="/images/japan16/2023-05-11_170348_00.JPG" alt="image">
This shot was taken close to our Hotel. Just look at those layers and layers of road. Feels so different from any European City, it feels like you are in a metropolis (not in a good way though).
<img src="/images/japan16/2023-05-11_201804_00.JPG" alt="image">
As for touristy stuff: We went to Dotonbori, walked around there, had some Takoyaki (Octopus bits in small batter balls covered in all kinds of sauces) and went to a bar to have some drinks.
<img src="/images/japan16/2023-05-11_204721_00.JPG" alt="image"></p>
<h1>Tokushima</h1>
<p>We had to wake up early the next day to pick up our rental car from the airport (see, there are my excuses why there were no blog posts in the last days). We got the car and went straight to Tokushima where we had our first stop of our five day road trip.</p>
<p>After the lasst super busy days, we were just taking it easy. It was nice to be on the road, relaxing our bodies in the seat of a car for once. The Japanese countryside is so pretty and driving in Japan is just a breeze. Sure, the speed limit is super low (70 to 100 km per hour on the expressway) but drivers are just super chill here. Nobody is stressing you out, people are looking out for each other. If people honk, they do it just very shortly, just to remind you of something not to show aggresion towards you.</p>
<p>Anyway, I took two pictures of Tokushima worth sharing:
<img src="/images/japan16/2023-05-12_161752_00.JPG" alt="image">
<img src="/images/japan16/2023-05-12_164138_00.JPG" alt="image"></p>
<h1>Iya-Valley (Middle of nowhere in Shikoku)</h1>
<p>Which leads me to today! We left Tokushima and went west. Sadly, it started raining today and never really stopped. We went to a Café that I wanted to visit ever since seeing it in a YouTube-Video: Haretoke Café. This hidden gem is in the Iya-Valley in Shikoku. The owner repurposed an old school into this café/hotel/sauna.
<img src="/images/japan16/2023-05-13_141031_00.JPG" alt="Haretoke Café">
This is what it looks like from the outside. You can still clearly see that this was once used as a school building.
<img src="/images/japan16/2023-05-13_154447_00.JPG" alt="image">
Since there was not much else to do around the area, we drove to a nearby hot spring (Onsen) which had an outdoor bath with natural spring water that smelled like sulfur. It was lovely! We could sit in the valley, surrounded by tall mountains that are covered in forests (see the picture above) and just relax while the rain kept on falling.</p>
<p>The following pictures show some impressions of just how beautiful Shikoku and the Iya-Valley are. I don't get, why those regions are not popular with foreign tourists. It is just super lovely here and so far, this is one of my favorite regions in all of Japan. But part of the appeal is also that there are not so many tourists here so there's that.</p>
<p>Just have a look for yourself…
<img src="/images/japan16/2023-05-13_181621_00.JPG" alt="image">
<img src="/images/japan16/2023-05-13_182918_00.JPG" alt="image">
<img src="/images/japan16/2023-05-13_183537_00.JPG" alt="image">
<img src="/images/japan16/2023-05-13_183824_00.JPG" alt="image">
<img src="/images/japan16/2023-05-13_183933_00.JPG" alt="image"></p>

    ]]>
      </content>
    </entry>
  
    
    <entry>
      <title>Hiking Mount Tsurugi</title>
      <link href="https://jonas.place/posts/hiking-mount-tsurugi/"/>
      <updated>2023-05-15T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <id>https://jonas.place/posts/hiking-mount-tsurugi/</id>
      <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[
      <p>When planning our journey in Japan, we wanted to go on a &quot;proper&quot; hike. This hike was to Tsurugi San (Mount Tsurugi). To get there, we had to drive for about 2 hours (the distance was not far, about 40 km but the roads are windy and speed limits are low). On our way there, we stopped several times to have a look at local landmarks and marvel at the nature surrounding us.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Check out an interactive Map of the places we visited <a href="https://wanderlog.com/view/ipgoeoyijw/japan-trip/shared">here</a>. I will update this map as we continue our Journey. This post is about Day 17.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><img src="/images/japan17/2023-05-14_081906_00.JPG" alt="Iya Valley opening shot">
Iya Valley is a very pretty location.
<img src="/images/japan17/2023-05-14_084607_00.JPG" alt="Hi Valley">
There is even something like <a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Horseshoe_Bend_(Arizona)">horseshoe bend</a> in Iya Valley, though they call it ひ valley (Hi Valley), because it looks like the Hiragana Letter Hi (ひ).
<img src="/images/japan17/2023-05-14_091112_00.JPG" alt="Suspension Bridge">
These wooden suspension bridges are what Iya valley is famous for. They used to be constructed from just wood but are now rebuilt and reinforced with steel ropes. From a distance, they don't look like much at all. When we saw the first bridge our first impulse was to skip them (also because the toll to pass one of those bridges is 3.50€ per person.).
<img src="/images/japan17/2023-05-14_103529_00.JPG" alt="Walking on Wooden Beams">
The second pair of bridges you couldn't see from afar tho and so we decided to splurge on this toll and each got a ticket to walk across the bridge. Stepping foot on the bridge was quite an experience! Just look how far the individual wooden beams are from each other! You can fit a foot in between two beams if you are not careful.
<img src="/images/japan17/2023-05-14_101534_00.JPG" alt="Scarecrow Village">
We also passed through Scarecrow Village. Since the Island of Shikoku has a problem with depopulation (older people dying and younger people leaving the rural areas for more prosperous regions), a local artist got the idea to &quot;rebuilt&quot; the co-villagers that either left or passed away. There are also some scarecrows that are modeled after reporters like this one from german public broadcast service &quot;NDR&quot;. All in all it was quite a creepy village and we decided not to stick around for too long.</p>
<p>After 2 hours of driving, we finally reached our destination: The bottom of mount Tsurugi! Sadly, the weather shifted for the worst and we got a lot of rain and mist, so we decided to cut the planned hike to the top of the mountain short and took the chairlift which took us to the approximate halfway point of the hike.
<img src="/images/japan17/2023-05-14_181232_00.JPG" alt="View from the top of Tsurugisan onto a hiking path">
From there, it was just about 40 minutes of hiking to the top. Even though it was not a hard hike we were still quite happy to reach the destination and skip the rain for once. The image above is the hiking trail as seen from the mountain hut that we hiked to.</p>
<p>We had booked a room in the hut for an overnight stay and luckily, we could check in early. We got into our (tiny) room, turned on the Kotatsu (table with a heating element below it and a blanket that you can stick your feet under) and immediately fell into a deep sleep. We slept about 2.5 hours. After waking up, it was already time for dinner!<br>
It was a simple meal but we enjoyed it a lot.
<img src="/images/japan17/2023-05-14_182517_00.JPG" alt="Tsuruigsan view">
After dinner, it luckily cleared up a bit and we could see some of the surrounding mountains, covered in clouds. The view was very beautiful.
<img src="/images/japan17/2023-05-14_182709_00.JPG" alt="View into the valley from Tsurugisan">
Moments like these are why I love hiking so much. The calm and quiet of the mountain plus this wonderful view are just so healing for the soul.</p>
<p>In the hut it was &quot;lights out&quot; at 9 PM. We decided to sleep at 9 PM and watch the sunrise on the next morning which is at 4:49 AM.
<img src="/images/japan17/2023-05-15_050637_00.JPG" alt="Sunrise Picture from Tsurugisan">
We woke up at 4:15 AM when the staff of the hut got to work and ran around. We got out of bed and were greeted by a dim red and yellow glow at the horizon with a thick layer of clouds underneath it. This view was already breathtaking (it was still a good half hour until the real sunrise). Gradually, it got brighter and brighter and we were joined by our fellow co hut-dwellers. The picture above doesn't do the beauty of this sunris justice but I think you get the picture.
<img src="/images/japan17/2023-05-15_052025_00.JPG" alt="Reflections on the path on Tsurugisan">
The rays of early mountain sun illuminated the paths on top of the mountain. It didn't look like a moon-base anymore.
<img src="/images/japan17/2023-05-15_052343_00.JPG" alt="Binocular on top of Tsurugisan">
<img src="/images/japan17/2023-05-15_055513_00.JPG" alt="Eating hall window in the sunlight">
After having breakfast at 6 AM in the eating area of the hut (thanks for the photo idea, Esther), we made our way down the mountain again.
<img src="/images/japan17/2023-05-15_070716_00.JPG" alt="Clouds on the hiking trail of Tsurugisan">
Sadly, our old friends, the clouds were back too! The whole path looked like a mistery-forest.
<img src="/images/japan17/2023-05-15_072905_00.JPG" alt="View into the cloudy valley from Hiking Trail of Tsurugisan">
Luckily, it also cleared up once we reached the halfway point, so we had some nice scenic views.</p>

    ]]>
      </content>
    </entry>
  
    
    <entry>
      <title>Shodoshima</title>
      <link href="https://jonas.place/posts/shodoshima/"/>
      <updated>2023-05-17T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <id>https://jonas.place/posts/shodoshima/</id>
      <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[
      <p>Right now, we are sitting on a ferry leaving Shōdoshima, an Island in the Japanese Inland sea. We spent the last 48 hours on this beautiful island.<br>
When planning our trip to Japan while looking for accomodations in Shikoku, a guesthouse on Shōdoshima island kept popping up again and again. It looked beautiful and we wanted to spend some time on an island with nice beaches.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Check out an interactive Map of the places we visited <a href="https://wanderlog.com/view/ipgoeoyijw/japan-trip/shared">here</a>. I will update this map as we continue our Journey. This post is about Day 18 and 19.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>We drove from Tsurugisan to Takamatsu, which is about 80 km apart from each other. This drive took us three hours (most roads had a speed limit of 50 kph).</p>
<p><img src="/images/japan19/2023-05-15_133924_00.jpg" alt="Ferry to Shōdoshima Island">
We took the ferry from Takamatsu to Shōdoshima. It had beautiful colors. When stopping our car on the ferry, employees of the ferry put wedges under our tires to keep the car from moving about. I never saw anyone do this on any ferry ever before.
<img src="/images/japan19/2023-05-15_123538_00.JPG" alt="Bicycle with wedges">
They even put wedges under the tires of bicycles – that is Japanese dedication!
<img src="/images/japan19/2023-05-15_140918_00.JPG" alt="Angel Road on Shōdoshima">
When we reached Shōdoshima, we checked out Angel Road first. This strip of land only appears on low tide. We were lucky that it just happened to be low tide when we arrived. I was surprised at how beautiful the beach was! Of course, nobody was bathing in the water (bathing in the sea is not really a thing in Japan, surprisingly).
<img src="/images/japan19/2023-05-15_155021_00.jpg" alt="View from our guesthouse room">
We then drove accross the island and got to our accomodation (Sen Guesthouse, it is absolutely gorgeous!). This was the view from our room!<br>
The room had completely new Tatami (the stuff on the floor) and comfy Futons.
<img src="/images/japan19/2023-05-15_163954_00.JPG" alt="Private Beach of the accomodation">
This was the private beach of Sen Guesthouse. Since this guesthouse is a bit far from the rest of the island (5km to the next Convenience Store), it is also very calm and relaxing there.
<img src="/images/japan19/2023-05-16_094654_00.JPG" alt="Concrete observation tower 1">
We checked out this concrete observation tower that somebody built into the natural landscape on top of the mountain that is in the middle of Shōdoshima. I like the contrast of this concrete structure to the surrounding nature.
<img src="/images/japan19/2023-05-16_095023_00.JPG" alt="Concrete observation tower 2">
The view from the observation tower was quite bad. Even though it was situated on top of the mountain you could not see very much since the trees surrounding the observation deck were just as tall as the observation deck itself.
<img src="/images/japan19/2023-05-16_095254_00.JPG" alt="Concrete observation tower 3">
<img src="/images/japan19/2023-05-16_100136_00.JPG" alt="Observation deck">
We also checked out another platform from which you had a much better view of Shōdoshima. The island does not have that many tourists compared to other places in Japan, which was surprising to me.
<img src="/images/japan19/2023-05-16_112439_00.JPG" alt="Caribean Vibes on Shōdoshima">
On the island, the landscape is very different from north to south. In the north, there are red rocks, very little vegetation – it looks like a desert. The south of the island is green with palm trees and has a carribean vibe.</p>
<p>Traffic is quite slow on Shōdoshima. The maximum allowed speed is 60 kph with most roads having a speed limit of just 40 kph. To travel the island from north to south you need about an hour (for 25km). This low travel speed also allows you to enjoy the landscape and just relax a bit more.
<img src="/images/japan19/2023-05-16_133656_00.JPG" alt="Soy Sauce Factory">
Shōdoshima is famous for three things:</p>
<ol>
<li>Soy Sauce</li>
<li>Sake (Japanese Rice Wine)</li>
<li>Olives</li>
</ol>
<p>Naturally, we checked out all three of those things on Shōdoshima. Sake and Olives were not that special to us since those two things are produced in lots of places but Soy Sauce is quite unique to Shōdoshima. The island climate is warm all year round but not too hot which is perfect for brewing Soy Sauce as we learned.</p>
<p>We went to Yamaroku, one of the few places left in the world that still produces Soy Sauce like it was produced for centuries before modern processes were developed. Nowadays, only 1% of all Soy Sauce production is done in the way that Yamaroku does it.<br>
The picture above shows were the Soy Sauce is &quot;produced&quot;. The ingredients Soy, Salt Water and Wheat rest in wooden barrels for at least 2 years were they ferment with naturally occuring microbes. The barrel that is on the rightmost side of the picture is about 150 years old and is the oldes barrel that Yamaroku has. The outside of this barrel is covered in white particles and kind of looks moldy up close.</p>
<p>We were not allowed to touch the barrels since touching them meant disturbing the microorganisms that live on the barrel. I later realized that I had seen this factory before: You can see it in the Netflix Series &quot;Salt Fat Acid Heat&quot; (obviously it is in the Salt episode).</p>
<p>Our tour guide of the factory had quite an interesting story. He was not Japanese but French and said to us that he does not gets to speak English that much. He had been looking for a job and just asked if he could work at the Soy Sauce factory without knowing Japanese. The owner said yes.<br>
When we asked him if he is interested in Soy Sauce he denied and said that he didn't like Soy Sauce that much. He was much more into Computers. Quite a funny guy actually.</p>
<p>After the tour of the factory, we tried all of the different Soy Sauces that Yamaroku produces and they were all equally great. It is like tasting a good french/swiss cheese after you only had mass-produced american processed cheese all your life. The taste is completely umami and not as salty as industrial soy sauces. We had Maple Ice Cream with Soy Sauce which was out of this world good! If you like Salted Caramel the combination of Maple and Soy Sauce will just blow you away!
<img src="/images/japan19/2023-05-16_173926_00.JPG" alt="Bento Shop in Shōdoshima">
For dinner, we went to different places but all of them were closed. This is a thing about Shōdoshima: You cannot really trust Google Maps or even the opening hours written on the places themselves. People will just decide to not open if they don't feel like it. Luckily, the Supermarket was open and we just got a bunch of delicious stuff from there and ate it on the front veranda of Sen Guesthouse.
<img src="/images/japan19/2023-05-16_175553_00.JPG" alt="Eat in Shōdoshima">
This was the second restaurant that was closed.</p>
<p>All in all, I would highly recommend to have a short stay on Shōdoshima. It is such a wonderful place that is not overcrowded, offers some amazing sights, tasty food and great local culture! There is even a craft beer brewery on Shōdoshima that we vistited which had an incredible Olive Imperial Gose made from olives from Shōdoshima. Next, we will go back to the big city.</p>

    ]]>
      </content>
    </entry>
  
    
    <entry>
      <title>Back to Japan again</title>
      <link href="https://jonas.place/posts/back-to-japan-again/"/>
      <updated>2024-11-10T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <id>https://jonas.place/posts/back-to-japan-again/</id>
      <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[
      <p>I am back in Japan! This time I chose November to see the beautiful fall colors.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Check out an interactive map of the places I visited <a href="https://wanderlog.com/view/rvadlvcbrq/japan-fall-2024/shared">here</a>. I will update this map as I continue my journey. This post is about days 0-2.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I arrived a couple of days ago but so far had no time to document anything. This blog post is a write-up of the last three days.</p>
<p>I didn't get much sleep on the plane, maybe 3 hours in total. I got off the plane, met up with the friend I am traveling with and had some pretty good ramen for 6.50€ at Haneda airport. For this trip we rented a car to explore the countryside of Japan. We picked it up at 5pm near the airport and were off. With not much sleep, getting thrown into left-hand traffic in a super busy city like Tokyo is not the best experience in the world. Google Maps predicted it should take us 2 hours to reach our first destination near Tokyo, but with traffic at its peak and me not being used to driving on a Japanese highway that much, it took us a good 3 hours to get there. One wrong exit on the highway alone cost us an hour. Would not recommend it. Lesson learned: add +30% to your driving time when traveling in Japan by car.</p>
<p>Luckily, we reached our country inn around 8pm. We learned that the place we chose to stay - Sano City - is famous for its ramen. So we had ramen for dinner a second time. This ramen felt much more &quot;home&quot;, it reminded me of the chicken broth my grandma used to make.</p>
<p>I really felt the jet lag that first night. I only slept 5 hours and woke up feeling pretty groggy.</p>
<p><img src="/images/2024-11-10-first-japan-post/2024-11-08_085153_00.jpeg" alt="The 'living room' of our inn">
I took the first real picture in the morning, this is the &quot;living room&quot; of our inn, a pretty nice guest house.</p>
<p>We ate a small breakfast at the guest house and headed off to the first proper destination: One of the oldest onsens (hot spring) in Japan: Sekizenkan Kashoutei.
<img src="/images/2024-11-10-first-japan-post/2024-11-08_132009_00.jpeg" alt="First trip to the oldest onsen in Japan">
The bridge leading to the onsen was inspiration to a famous Miyazaki movie: Spirited Away. The atmosphere was pretty magical there.
<img src="/images/2024-11-10-first-japan-post/2024-11-08_132908_00.jpeg" alt="Onsen Town">
The town itself also kind of reminded me of the first scenes of the movie where the main characters parents eat food at a market and turn into pigs.
<img src="/images/2024-11-10-first-japan-post/2024-11-08_161041_00.jpeg" alt="Next onsen town: Kusatsu Onsen">
We reached our final destination around 3pm after driving through lots of scenic roads: Kusatsu Onsen. Kusatsu Onsen is a famous onsen town that is popular with Japanese tourists. We didn't see many western tourists there at all. Above, you can see the main &quot;attraction&quot; on the main square of the town. The hot spring water flows from the mountains through the town and then falls down in this waterfall that you see here. The whole town has manhole covers which have steam rising from them from the hot spring water flowing under them. This makes for a quite magical atmosphere, especially when the outside temperatures are a bit lower.</p>
<p>Since the onsen water has a high sulfur content, the smell is hard to get used to at first. It smells of rotten eggs everywhere.</p>
<p>The high mineral content of the spring water colors the areas it touches in blue teal, creating some unique looks (see picture above).
<img src="/images/2024-11-10-first-japan-post/2024-11-08_175438_00.jpeg" alt="Kusatsu Onsen at night">
We had dinner and went to an outdoor onsen. It got dark in the meantime and we had to climb a bit up a hill to get there. The way they illuminated the steaming hot spring water made the journey there so much more mystical.</p>
<p>Usually, onsen baths are taken same-sex only. But on friday nights, Kusatsu Onsen has mixed-sex onsens. We saw a lot of couples going to the onsen together. Not thinking anything, we got undressed and wanted to go into the hot water but were quickly called back by a well-meaning english-speaking person. We learned that you have to cover your private parts in the mixed-sex onsen but luckily, they handed out free bath shorts for everyone. One side-note: Japan is usually pretty strict with forbidding entry to tattooed individuals, but my friend had no issues with his tattoos in Kusatsu.</p>
<p>After the onsen, we felt warm although the outside temperature dropped to close to 0ºC. We finished the night at a local bar and went back to our Ryokan (guest house).
<img src="/images/2024-11-10-first-japan-post/2024-11-09_092347_00.jpeg" alt="Onsen in the Ryokan">
The Ryokan had its own private onsen which was a great addition. Taking hot baths is so relaxing, especially after sitting in a car for so long! I took a bath in the morning to wake up and get ready for the day.</p>
<p>We had a big journey ahead of us: 4 hours road trip from Kusatsu Onsen to Niigata. From Niigata, we wanted to take a ferry to Sado island and spend some time there.</p>
<p>Again, traffic predictions were not very accurate and the prediction of 3.5 hours turned into 4.5-5 hours. We didn't account for these inaccuracies and had a pretty stressful journey and almost missed our ferry!
<img src="/images/2024-11-10-first-japan-post/2024-11-09_161155_00.jpeg" alt="Niigata from the Ferry">
Luckily, we caught the ferry 10 minutes before its departure and were off. The adrenaline was still high when we saw this beautiful sunset from the ship. The Niigata skyline got smaller and smaller in the distance.</p>
<p><img src="/images/2024-11-10-first-japan-post/2024-11-09_163422_00.jpeg" alt="Sun setting like a bowl of ramen">
The sunset and looked like a bowl of Ramen touching the sea. Only in Japan!
<br><small>You can even see a small spoon sticking out on the right side if you look closely!</small></p>

    ]]>
      </content>
    </entry>
  
    
    <entry>
      <title>Sado Island</title>
      <link href="https://jonas.place/posts/sado-island/"/>
      <updated>2024-11-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <id>https://jonas.place/posts/sado-island/</id>
      <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[
      <p>In the last blog post, I wrote about how we just about caught a ferry to Sado Island. What I omitted was this: We didn't actually bring a car to Sado Island. We kinda assumed it would be feasible to bring a car to the island via ferry. What we didn't check is the price to transport a car to the island. Now for the kicker: Transporting a semi-large car (which we sadly got from the rental company) would have cost us the equivalent of 240€. We were not ready to spend this amount on transporting a car to an island for just two days, so we left the car in Niigata in a parking garage and took off without it.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Check out an interactive map of the places I visited <a href="https://wanderlog.com/view/rvadlvcbrq/japan-fall-2024/shared">here</a>. I will update this map as I continue my journey. This post is about day 3.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>We were worried that the buses might not run on the weekend. Since it was a Saturday and we would be arriving quite late (after 6pm), we were afraid that we might not be able to catch the bus that would have taken us to our accommodation. We tried to call the bus company on Sado Island the morning of the trip, but with my limited Japanese it was quite difficult to find out if the bus was actually running or not. (A simple question like &quot;When is the last bus from the port to xyz station?&quot; in simple Japanese was answered with a good 30 seconds of... intermediate Japanese).</p>
<p>We decided to improvise and might have taken a taxi if nothing else had worked out. But when we arrived, there was a bus waiting for us, perfectly timed with the arrival of the ferry!</p>
<p>Our host was very friendly and even picked us up from the bus stop.
We had a 30 square meter room (huge for Japan) filled to the brim with hi-fi equipment, old records and speakers from various manufacturers. We also had a huge 85 inch(?) TV, a complete living room set and a bunch of other stuff.</p>
<p>We were a bit surprised by all this, ate dinner and went to bed.</p>
<p><img src="/images/2024-11-11-sado-island/2024-11-10_093532_00.jpeg" alt="Local second-hand shop">
The next morning we explored Sado Island and the area around our accommodations. The island has many cafes, bars, restaurants and shops of all kinds. Near our accommodation there was a second-hand shop run by an old lady. The things there were so cute and affordable and the old lady gave us a handmade bag at the end.
<img src="/images/2024-11-11-sado-island/2024-11-10_094245_00.jpeg" alt="Flower stand on farmers market">
We were lucky because the farmers' market was just being set up as we took our morning walk.
<img src="/images/2024-11-11-sado-island/2024-11-10_094306_00.jpeg" alt="A seller selling something out of a van">
<img src="/images/2024-11-11-sado-island/2024-11-10_095712_00.jpeg" alt="Japanese shopping-arcade">
In Sado, there are several of these arcades that all look the same and are smaller than the typical shopping arcades found all over Japan.
<img src="/images/2024-11-11-sado-island/2024-11-10_100005_00.jpeg" alt="Aikawa street">
A typical street in Sado Island.
<img src="/images/2024-11-11-sado-island/2024-11-10_133604_00.jpeg" alt="Split mountain">
The main goal of the day was to see this mountain. It looks vaguely like <a href="https://zelda.fandom.com/wiki/Dueling_Peaks">this mountain</a> from The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom.</p>
<p>The mountain looks like that because people dug into it by hand to get the gold it contained. Sado Island is famous for this gold mining, which is no longer going on. Mining stopped in 1989.</p>
<p>To actually see the mountain, you have to visit the gold mining museum. The museum itself is not that exciting, but it explains how Sado Island became what it is today.
<img src="/images/2024-11-11-sado-island/2024-11-10_142013_00.jpeg" alt="Soft ice cream covered in gold flakes">
We ended our visit to the gold mine with a gold covered ice cream. Kind of gimmicky, but that's typical of Japan sometimes.</p>

    ]]>
      </content>
    </entry>
  
    
    <entry>
      <title>Roadtrip to Tsuruoka</title>
      <link href="https://jonas.place/posts/roadtrip-to-tsuruoka/"/>
      <updated>2024-11-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <id>https://jonas.place/posts/roadtrip-to-tsuruoka/</id>
      <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[
      <blockquote>
<p>Check out an interactive map of the places I visited <a href="https://wanderlog.com/view/rvadlvcbrq/japan-fall-2024/shared">here</a>. I will update this map as I continue my journey. This post is about day 4 and 5.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>We took the ferry back from Sado island to Niigata.
<img src="/images/2024-11-12-to-morioka/2024-11-11_094217_00.jpeg" alt="Chairs inside the ferry">
The ferry was a bit older this time and had picturesque pastel chairs inside.
<img src="/images/2024-11-12-to-morioka/2024-11-11_112614_00.jpeg" alt="Lighthouse seen from the ferry windows">
Near Niigata Harbor, we passed this lighthouse, which at some point perfectly matched the blue and white pattern on the windows of the ferry. That's when I took this picture.</p>
<p>Back in Niigata, we picked up the car and paid our 10€ parking fee for 48 hours. Our next destination: Tsuroka.
We booked this accommodation because it's about halfway between Niigata and our northernmost destination: Morioka.</p>
<p>The lodging was an old ryokan (guesthouse) in Tsuruoka.
Both dinner and breakfast were delicious teishoku (Japanese set meals) made with local ingredients and prepared with care. I took some pictures of the food, but they don't do it justice, so I'll skip posting them.</p>
<p>In the morning, we got up early and went to the Dewasanzan Shrine which was just around the corner from the Ryokan.
<img src="/images/2024-11-12-to-morioka/2024-11-12_084244_00.jpeg" alt="Hiking to Mount Haguro">
After walking down a steep set of stone stairs, we reached this red bridge that led us onto the trail.</p>
<p>We were very lucky that it was still early, as there were not many other people around and we had the opportunity to take some scenic pictures.
<img src="/images/2024-11-12-to-morioka/2024-11-12_085803_00.jpeg" alt="Five Story Pagoda">
On the left you can see a 1000 year old cedar tree, which is considered to be the grandfather of the forest, on the right there is a five story pagoda.
<img src="/images/2024-11-12-to-morioka/2024-11-12_090119_00.jpeg" alt="Light falling through the trees at mount Haguro">
We were also very lucky with the light, the sun was just shining through the leaves and with the early morning mist the light rays were visible.
<img src="/images/2024-11-12-to-morioka/2024-11-12_090518_00.jpeg" alt="Five Story Pagoda up close">
The five story pagoda in relation to a regular sized human.
<img src="/images/2024-11-12-to-morioka/2024-11-12_092017_00.jpeg" alt="Going up the mountain">
After the tree and the pagoda, the real hike began: stone stairs upon stone stairs. You couldn't even see the end of them.
<img src="/images/2024-11-12-to-morioka/2024-11-12_093036_00.jpeg" alt="Lightfall on top the mountain">
Luckily, there were always flat sections in between the steep stairs.
<img src="/images/2024-11-12-to-morioka/2024-11-12_103949_00.jpeg" alt="Enjoying the view">
Sometimes we just had to stop and admire the beauty of the forest.</p>
<p>At the top of the mountain there is a Shinto shrine, a museum, and some other buildings. The beauty of the shrine paled in comparison to the hike through nature that preceded it.
<img src="/images/2024-11-12-to-morioka/2024-11-12_143213_00.jpeg" alt="Oufukasawa Bridge in Autumn">
On our way to our next destination, we made a quick stop at the Oufukasawa Bridge, which is known for its beautiful fall colors. The further north we got, the more fall colors we saw.</p>

    ]]>
      </content>
    </entry>
  
    
    <entry>
      <title>Morioka, Day one</title>
      <link href="https://jonas.place/posts/morioka-day-one/"/>
      <updated>2024-11-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <id>https://jonas.place/posts/morioka-day-one/</id>
      <content type="html">
        <![CDATA[
      <p>After a few more hours of driving, we reached Morioka, a city way up north. We checked into our hotel, which was conveniently located and had cheap parking. After resting for a while, we decided to go out for dinner, we happened to find an amazing ramen spot that had the tastiest tsukemen (dipped noodles) ever: Menya Iori. Check out the interactive map to find out more.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Check out an interactive map of the places I visited <a href="https://wanderlog.com/view/rvadlvcbrq/japan-fall-2024/shared">here</a>. I will update this map as I continue my journey. This post is about day 6.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>We decided to spend the next day exploring Morioka (it is a small city and 24 hours are definitely enough to see everything) and another day to go on a day trip to the nature around Morioka.
<img src="/images/2024-11-13-morioka/2024-11-13_090818_00.jpeg" alt="Morioka Shopping Street">
The main street of Morioka in the city center is this street: Odori Street. It is a semi-covered arcade that offers protection from the elements. Slow traffic speeds allow for easy and relaxed strolling.
<img src="/images/2024-11-13-morioka/2024-11-13_092104_00.jpeg" alt="Morioka City View">
If you continue down Odori towards the eastern part of the city, you will reach this part of the city where you can find most of the (good) cafes and restaurants compressed into just a few alleys (left side of the picture).
<img src="/images/2024-11-13-morioka/2024-11-13_100925_00.jpeg" alt="Autumn leaves at a stream close to Morioka Castle park">
Across the street is Tsurugaike, a public park that connects directly to Morioka Castle. The park was so carefully arranged that it almost looked artificial. The fall leaves were at their peak and we finally saw what we came to Japan for. See for yourself on the next three pictures
<img src="/images/2024-11-13-morioka/2024-11-13_101247_00.jpeg" alt="Autumn leaves at a stream close to Morioka Castle park">
<img src="/images/2024-11-13-morioka/2024-11-13_101400_00.jpeg" alt="Autumn leaves at a stream close to Morioka Castle park">
<img src="/images/2024-11-13-morioka/2024-11-13_102228_00.jpeg" alt="Autumn Foliage">
We walked around a bit more, exploring Morioka Castle, which is no longer a castle. It was destroyed in 1874 and the castle grounds were turned into a park.</p>
<p>We had lunch at Pairon, where you can eat Jajamen, a noodle dish that Morioka is famous for. Jajamen are slightly thicker than ramen noodles, chewy, almost overcooked in consistency, and are served with miso and freshly cut cucumber pieces. You can add garlic, vinegar, and chili oil to your heart's content. The special thing about Jajamen: When you are almost finished eating, you can crack a raw egg over your leftovers, and the server will add hot soup stock and more miso paste to your noodles, turning them into soup. You can practically enjoy two dishes in one. We were so full after all that food that we decided to go out for coffee.
<img src="/images/2024-11-13-morioka/2024-11-13_154949_00.jpeg" alt="Coffee at the river">
Morioka is famous for its coffee culture and nowhere in Japan have I found a higher density of coffee shops per square meter than here. Normally you cannot sit outside in a cafe or restaurant, but we found a place where not only could you sit outside, but they also had seats right by the river, which you can see in the picture above. This is very unusual for Japan but quite enjoyable for us!
<img src="/images/2024-11-13-morioka/2024-11-13_112821_00.jpeg" alt="Statue in the Nanshoso House garden">
After coffee, we went to an old Japanese house, Nanshoso, which we found while researching leaf spots in Morioka. We were not disappointed. The courtyard was beautifully landscaped with fall colors everywhere.
<img src="/images/2024-11-13-morioka/2024-11-13_113141_00.jpeg" alt="Nanshoso House view">
A view from the garden to the Nanshoso house.
<img src="/images/2024-11-13-morioka/2024-11-13_143241_00.jpeg" alt="Side-Alley in Morioka">
Above you can see a small side alley in Morioka to showcase how quaint most streets look there.
<img src="/images/2024-11-13-morioka/2024-11-13_150656_00.jpeg" alt="Largest shrine in Morioka">
In the last hours of daylight, we went to Morioka Hachimangu, which is almost 1000 years old and the largest shrine in Iwate Prefecture.</p>
<p>In the picture above, you can see a small shrine on the grounds of the main shrine with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ema_(Shinto)">Ema</a> hanging to the left and right.</p>

    ]]>
      </content>
    </entry>
  
</feed>